(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-02T22:49:25.001772",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
こよりスケッチ テレリ〜ン はい！かわいい！
Koyori Sketch! Tadar~! Yes! So cute!
せーの！はい！
Ready, set, go! Yes!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
研究室らしい実験感！
A lab-like experimental feel!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うわー！近未来の実験感！
Whoa! A futuristic experimental feel!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
こよりの助手くんはネムネム！
Koyori's Assistant-kun is sleepy!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うわー！ヘルプー！
Whoa! Help!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うわー！呑んべぇだー！
Whoa! A drunkard!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
頭脳なんでね！見切りー！
I'm the brain after all! Evasion!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
可愛いです！ふやー！
So cute! Huyaa~!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
オッケー！極夜です！
Okay! It's polar night!
うわーーーーー！
Whaaaaaa!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
波打ち際は空気です！
The shoreline is just air!
はい！お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes! Big brother! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます！そうですが何か？
I always stock frozen udon! Got a problem with that?
やったー！証明完了 Q.E.D.！
Yay! Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
コックだろ コック！いっちゃー！
It's a cook, right, a cook! Here we go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
こよりはひよこ ピヨピヨ！
Koyori is a chick, peep peep!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
大丈夫かな？ ういういういうい！
Are we okay? Ui ui ui ui!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ふやー！行きませんね！
Huyaa! Not going!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
思い切りましょう！
Let's go all out!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ウルフプログラムはイケそう！
The Wolf Program looks good to go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ハイモード！
High mode!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うー！うわー！
Ooh! Whoa!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
波打ち際は空気です！
The shoreline is just air!
はい！お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes! Big brother! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます！そうですが何か？
I always stock frozen udon! Got a problem with that?
やったー！私の戦闘力は54万です！
Yay! My battle power is 540,000!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
あ！私は風船です！
Ah! I'm a balloon!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
バニラの香りちょうだいよ！
Give me that vanilla scent!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
タテノコだね！タテノコ！
It's a vertical saw, right! Vertical saw!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
あー！150、50！
Ah! 150, 50!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
チャンプは乗り物ではありません！
Champ is not a vehicle!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
骨つきラーメンです！
Bone-in ramen!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
尻尾フリフリダメですか？
Is tail wagging no good?
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
みんなの応援がいっちばんだよ！
Everyone's support is number one!
右手ー！
Right hand!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
波打ち際は空気です！
The shoreline is just air!
はい！お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes! Big brother! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます！そうですが何か？
I always stock frozen udon! Got a problem with that?
やったー！ジ・エンドー！
Yay! The End!
極夜よー！
It's polar night!
極夜だよー！
せーの！極夜です！
Ready, set... It's polar night!
はい！ハッシュタグ #こより実験中
Yes! Hashtag #KoyoriExperiment
オッケー！こよは頭脳です！頭脳派ですか？
Okay! Koyo is the brain! Are you the brainy type?
はい！やったー！
Yes! Yay!
こよりスケッチ テレリ〜ン はい！かわいい！
Koyori Sketch! Tadar~! Yes! So cute!
せーの！はい！
Ready, set, go! Yes!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
研究室らしい実験感！
A lab-like experimental feel!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うわー！近未来の実験感！
Whoa! A futuristic experimental feel!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
こよりの助手くんはネムネム！
Koyori's Assistant-kun is sleepy!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うわー！ヘルプー！
Whoa! Help!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うわー！呑んべぇだー！
Whoa! A drunkard!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
頭脳なんでね！見切りー！
I'm the brain after all! Evasion!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
可愛いです！ふやー！
So cute! Huyaa~!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
オッケー！極夜です！
Okay! It's polar night!
うわーーーーー！
Whaaaaaa!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
波打ち際は空気です！
The shoreline is just air!
はい！お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes! Big brother! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます！そうですが何か？
I always stock frozen udon! Got a problem with that?
やったー！証明完了 Q.E.D.！
Yay! Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
コックだろ コック！いっちゃー！
It's a cook, right, a cook! Here we go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
こよりはひよこ ピヨピヨ！
Koyori is a chick, peep peep!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
大丈夫かな？ ういういういうい！
Are we okay? Ui ui ui ui!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ふやー！行きませんね！
Huyaa! Not going!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
思い切りましょう！
Let's go all out!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ウルフプログラムはイケそう！
The Wolf Program looks good to go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
ハイモード！
High mode!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
うー！うわー！
Ooh! Whoa!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
波打ち際は空気です！
The shoreline is just air!
はい！お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes! Big brother! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます！そうですが何か？
I always stock frozen udon! Got a problem with that?
やったー！私の戦闘力は54万です！
Yay! My battle power is 540,000!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
あ！私は風船です！
Ah! I'm a balloon!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
バニラの香りちょうだいよ！
Give me that vanilla scent!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
タテノコだね！タテノコ！
It's a vertical saw, right! Vertical saw!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
あー！150、50！
Ah! 150, 50!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
チャンプは乗り物ではありません！
Champ is not a vehicle!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
骨つきラーメンです！
Bone-in ramen!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
尻尾フリフリダメですか？
Is tail wagging no good?
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
みんなの応援がいっちばんだよ！
Everyone's support is number one!
右手ー！
Right hand!
やったー！間に合ったー！
Yay! Made it in time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です！
Mayonnaise is a beverage!
波打ち際は空気です！
The shoreline is just air!
はい！フラスコ、試験管、冷凍保存は準備してますかー？
Yes! Are your flasks, test tubes, and freezer storage ready?
せーの、こんこよー！
Ready, set, Konkoyo!
こんこよーりだよー！
It's Konkoyori!
せーの、こんこよーです！
Ready, set, it's Konkoyo!
そう！はい！ハッシュタグこより実験中ですよ！
That's right! Yes! The hashtag is #KoyoriExperimenting!
オーケー！こよーは頭脳！頭脳ですかー？
Okay! Koyo is the brain! Are you the brain?
はい！やったー！こよりスケッチ！てれーん！
Yes! Yay! Koyori sketch! Ta-da!
はい！せーの！
Yes! Ready, set!
はい！はい！はい！研究者らしい試験管！
Yes! Yes! Yes! A test tube fitting for a researcher!
はい！はい！はい！未来の試験管！
Yes! Yes! Yes! A futuristic test tube!
はい！はい！はい！有料入場者はねむ...
Yes! Yes! Yes! Paid members get...
女のガチトーク 第4回ー！
Girls' Serious Talk - Episode 4!
イエーイ！やったー！4回目だー！
Yay! We made it to the 4th episode!
4回目です！そして今回もなんと！ゲストがいます！やったー！
It's our 4th episode! And once again, we have a guest today! Yay!
イエーイ！お邪魔してます！いらっしゃい！
Yay! Thanks for having me! Welcome!
ということで、いらっしゃいませー！本日はノエル先輩が遊びに来てくれました！
So, welcome! Today Noel-senpai has come to visit us!
よろしくお願いしますー！
Please welcome her! / Thank you for having me!
ほんじゃ、自己紹介がてら、今日の意気込みなど聞いてみましょうか！じゃあ、ラミたん！
So, while introducing ourselves, let's hear everyone's enthusiasm for today! First, Lamy-tan!
はい！ホロライブ5期生の顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！今日もどんな相談が来ているのか楽しみです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! I'm Yukihana Lamy from Hololive 5th Gen, whose face is her liver! I'm looking forward to seeing what advice requests we got today! Nice to meet you!
はい！そして、ずのーずのー頭脳の博衣こよりだよ！毎回どんどんマシュマロが増えている気がします！
Yes! And I'm the brain, brain, brain, Hakui Koyori! I feel like we're getting more and more Marshmallows every time!
本当に嬉しくて！あとはみんなが結構ね、恋愛してるんだなとホクホクしております！今日もよろしくお願いします！
It makes me so happy! And I feel warm inside seeing that everyone is in love! Let me be in your care again today!
そして！ゲストのノエル先輩！どうですか、この番組の印象は？
And next, our guest, Noel-senpai! What's your impression of this show?
はい！皆さま、こんまっする！ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！
Hi, everyone! Kon-muscle! I'm Shirogane Noel from Hololive 3rd Gen!
いや、ずっとね、ちょっと興味があり... こよちゃんとかに『あれってゲストどんな感じになってるの？』ってチラチラ...
Honestly, I've been interested for a long time... I kept asking Koyori, 'So how do guests work on that show?' while dropping hints...
『いつでも開いてますよ』みたいな感じのちょっとかまちょムーブをしたら、なんと今回お呼びいただきました！ありがとうございます！
Like 'My schedule is wide open!' And after making those attention-seeking moves, I was actually invited! Thank you so much!
嬉しい！これね、番組よく観てるんですけど、とっても人を選ぶと思っておりまして...（笑）
I'm so happy! I watch this show often, but I always felt like it requires a very specific kind of guest... (laughs)
まあ、もちろん存じ上げておりますのでね。この深～い時間にやるのにね、ぴったりの深い番組になってるので。
Well, I know full well what it's about, of course! Since it airs at such a late hour, it's a deep show perfect for late nights.
『行きたい』って言ってもらえるの、すごい嬉しかったんです！今日はよろしくお願いします！
When you said you'd like to have me on, I was thrilled! Let me be in your care today!
NGはない感じですかね？
Do you have any NG topics?
いや、もちろん！NGなんてありませんっ！
No, of course not! I have zero NG topics!
本当！？なかったの！？ないの！？
Really?! None at all?!
ない！まあ、皆さんの恋愛がどんな感じなのかっていうの次第なところはあるけど、団長的にはNGないかなって。
None! Well, it depends on what kind of love life situations everyone brings up, but as for me, I don't think I have any NGs.
やっぱこの番組も見させていただいてて、『団長だったらこんな気持ちだな』とか想像しながら観てたので、今のところNGは...
I've been watching this show thinking, 'If it were me, I'd feel like this,' so for now, NGs are...
今のところね！今日ちょっとぶっ飛んでたら、ちょっと分からないかも...（笑）
For now! Though if things get too crazy today, I might reconsider... (laughs)
まあ今日も同じくらいかなと思いますので！答えづらい時は『答えづらい』って言ってくださいね！無理強いはいたしません！
Well, I think today will be about the usual level! If anything is hard to answer, just say so clearly! We won't force you into anything!
それでは見ていきましょう！じゃあ1個目、ちょっとジャブで... これ行っていいですか？
Alright then, let me take a look! For the first one, just a little jab... Can I go with this one?
『こよちゃんは「ノエル先輩」呼びですが、団長はもっと打ち解けて愛称呼びしてほしいな～って、「マミリィ」並みの愛称考えちゃいませんか？』
"Koyo-chan calls her 'Noel-senpai,' but Dancho wants her to be more open and call her by a nickname. Why not come up with a nickname like 'Mamiry'?"
お～、いいじゃないですか！さっきの配信でも言ってくれていたのー？っていうメッセージが...
Ooh, isn't that nice! There's a message asking if she mentioned that in her earlier stream as well...
なんか、こよちゃんずっと『ノエル先輩』って呼んでくれてて... そろそろ先輩呼びじゃなくて、お近づきになりたいな～って...
Yeah, Koyori has always called me 'Noel-senpai'... So I was hoping that pretty soon, instead of calling me 'senpai,' we could get a bit closer...
色々と遊んでるし、呼び始めたら呼べそうな気がする！」「慣れないかもだけど、やっぱ慣れなんだよね！
We've hung out a lot, so I feel like once I start calling you that, it'll come naturally! / It might take time, but it really is a matter of habit!
ぜひ呼び... なん、なんだろうな？でも『ラミたん』『ノエたん』なのかな？」「ノエたん！？」「ノエたん！ノエ... ノエたん！
What would it be, though? Maybe 'Lamy-tan' and 'Noe-tan'? / 'Noe-tan'?! / 'Noe-tan'! Noe... Noe-tan!
「あ、ノエル…」「うん」
"Ah, Noel..." "Yeah."
「ノエたん」「呼びやすい」
"Noe-tan!" "It's easy to say."
「ラミたんも『ノエたん』だよね」「ね」
"Lamy-tan also calls her 'Noe-tan,' right?" "Yeah."
「ノエたん」「あ、ノエたんか」
"Noe-tan." "Ah, Noe-tan, huh?"
「ノエたん！」「ノエたん！」「イントネーション(笑)」
"Noe-tan!" "Noe-tan!" "The intonation! (laughs)"
「ノエたん」「ノエ…じゃあこれからはノエたんで」
"Noe-tan..." "Noe... So from now on, it's Noe-tan."
「行こうかにゃ」「あ、下がる方で」
"Shall we go with that?" "Ah, with the falling intonation."
「あ、下がる方で。じゃあちょっとやっていきたいと思います、今日は」
"Ah, falling pitch. Let's try going with that today."
「やったー！」「あ、いいですね」「いい！」
"Yay!" "Ah, that's nice." "Nice!"
「さらにちょっと打ち解けられそうになったところで…」
"Now that we seem to be getting even closer..."
「はい。じゃあこれ、これが本当のジャブですね」
"Yes. Now this, this is the real jab."
「えー、こちら」「お、来た」
"Um, this one." "Oh, here it comes!"
「『男1人で『ちいかわ』の映画を見に行っても大丈夫でしょうか？』」
"Is it okay for a guy to go see the Chiikawa movie alone?"
「『周りから白い目で見られたりしないでしょうか？少し不安です』」
"Will people give me cold looks? I'm a little anxious."
「『でも、おっさんもセイレーンちゃんや島二郎に会いたいんです』」
"'But this middle-aged guy wants to see Siren-chan and Shimajiro too.'"
「というのが来てますよ。どうですか？」
"That's what came in. What do you think?"
「おふたり」「え、ダメな理由ある？逆に」
"You two." "Wait, is there any reason it'd be bad? On the contrary..."
「ないない！むしろいいよね！」
"No, none! In fact, it's great!"
「だよね！」「いいよいいよー！」「可愛い！」
"Right!" "It's totally fine!" "Cute!"
「ね！そう、これ、こういうのね、結構配信でもすでに言ってるんですけど」
"Right! Yeah, we've actually mentioned things like this on stream before,"
「それでも悩み大きい…あの、リスナーさんがいたので」
"but there were still listeners who were deeply troubled, so..."
「何も恥ずかしくないよな」「そうなんだ」「ねー、恥ずかしくない！」「ないでしょ！」
"There's nothing to be ashamed of." "Really." "Yeah, nothing to be ashamed of!" "Right?!"
「だって、2人とも『ちいかわ』映画見に行ってるもんね」
"I mean, both of you went to see the Chiikawa movie, right?"
「うん、行ってる」「いたよね、男1人の客さん」「うん、いたいたいた！」
"Yeah, we went." "There were solo male customers, right?" "Yeah, totally!"
「居る居る。しかもグッズもいっぱい着けてる！」「分かる、分かる！」
"There are! Plus, they have tons of merch attached!" "I get it, I get it!"
「全然平気だよ」「ねー。もう『気にするな』というのをお伝えするために紹介しました」
"It's totally fine!" "Yeah. So I introduced this to tell you, 'Don't worry about it.'"
「はい」「はい！」
"Yes." "Yes!"
「しかも、ね、あの、第5弾発表されたからね！」「ねー！」
"Plus, you know, the 5th round of bonus items was announced!" "Yeah!"
「あ、そうだね！ねー！」「だから…」「目印アクセね」
"Ah, that's right! Yeah!" "So..." "The marker charms, right?"
「うん、ね！」「より行ってほしい」「ねー！ゲットしてきてほしいですよね」
"Yeah!" "We want you to go even more." "Right! We want you to go get them."
「ぜひ島二郎をゲットしてください、ぜひ！」「はい！ぜひぜひ！」
"Please go get Shimajiro, definitely!" "Yes! By all means!"
「はい。それでは続いてこちら行きましょう。女の子からです」
"All right. Then let's move on to the next one. It's from a girl."
「『3人は学生時代、スクールメイクなどしてましたか？』」
"'Did you three do school makeup back in your student days?'"
「『私もしたいのですがよく分からないので参考にしたいです。おすすめのコスメなどあれば聞きたい』」
"'I want to try it too, but I don't really know how, so I want to use your experience as a reference. I'd like to hear if you have any recommended cosmetics.'"
「『聞きたい』ってね。おすすめコスメは何個か来てました、女子が」
"'I'd like to hear.' We got several questions about recommended cosmetics from female viewers."
「あー、そうなんだ！」「送ってくれてるみたい。嬉しいですね」
"Ah, really?! Looks like they've been sending them in. That's nice."
「へー！ありがたいですね」
"Oh! We really appreciate it."
「してた？スクールメイク」
"Did you do school makeup?"
「スクールメイク…」「え、なんか薄メイクみたいな、ナチュラルメイク？」
"School makeup..." "Like light makeup, or natural makeup?"
「どうなんだろ。学校行く時にメイク、なのかな？あとは学生時代にメイクって持ってた？」
"I wonder. Is it makeup when going to school? Or did you do makeup during student days?"
「してた」「え、してた？」
"I did." "Huh, you did?"
「お、してた！」「え、学校行く時もしてた？」
"Oh, you did!" "Wait, you even did it when going to school?"
「してた」「えー！すごい！」「してたのか」
"I did." "Woah! Amazing!" "You did, huh?"
「けど…」「え、2人はしてなかった？」
"Though..." "Wait, you two didn't?"
「こよは…」「こよは学校行く時はしてなくて」
"Koyo..." "Koyo didn't do it when going to school,"
「あのお出かけの時に、ちょっと見よう見まねで言ってた」
"but when going out, I tried imitating what I saw."
「あー、なるほどなるほど」「ノエ先輩…ノエたん(笑)」
"Ah, I see, I see." "Noel-senpai... Noe-tan (laughs)"
「ノエたんは？」「あ、ノエた…ノエたんはね、あの…」
"What about Noe-tan?" "Ah, Noe-ta... Noe-tan, you know,"
「いや、でも、どうだ…その、スクールメイク…」
"Well, but how was it... like, school makeup..."
「学生時代から…え、高校とかってことだよね？」「あ、そうそうそう」
"From student days... wait, you mean high school and such, right?" "Ah, right, right, right."
「そうそう」「えー…」
"Yeah, yeah." "Hmm..."
「なんかね、興味はあったけど、してなかったかな…なんか厳しかった」
"Well, I was interested, but I don't think I did it... It was pretty strict."
「あー！学校が？」「学校が厳しくて…」
"Ah! The school was?" "The school was strict, and..."
「なんかしてる子はいたの」「うん」「でも、すぐ怒られてて」
"There were girls who did it." "Yeah." "But they got yelled at right away."
「あ、それあかん奴…それあかん奴だ」「うん、横目で見て、『あ、厳しいな』」
"Ah, that's a no-no... that's no good." "Yeah, I looked sideways and thought, 'Ah, they're strict.'"
「『で、まだ早いか』って思って」「あー」「そんな感じだった」
"And thought, 'So it's still too early for me.'" "Ah." "That's how it was."
「賢いと思うけどなー」「校則はそれぞれあるもんね」
"I think that was wise, though." "Well, every school has its own rules."
「え、お出かけの時もしてなかった？」「お出かけの時はね」
"Wait, you didn't do it when going out either?" "When going out,"
「ちょっとあの見よう見まねで、プチプラあるじゃん？」「あ、うんうん！わかる！」
"I tried imitating with cheap cosmetics, you know?" "Ah, yeah yeah! I get it!"
「そう、だから400円とか500円の…」「うんうん」
"Yeah, so like 400 or 500 yen..." "Yeah yeah."
「クリームチークとか買って、チークだけ塗ってた黒歴史がある」
"I bought cream blush and only applied blush—I have a dark past like that."
「え、チークだけ？！」「黒歴史っていうほどでもないだろ！」
"Wait, blush only?!" "That's not really much of a dark past!"
「いや、今思うと…」「たしかに、でも…」
"No, thinking about it now..." "Indeed, but..."
「やっぱさ、トータル大事じゃん？全体の」「そうだね」
"I mean, total balance is important, right? Overall." "That's true."
「そういうの気にせず、口紅だけとかさ、チークだけっていう」
"Without caring about that, doing just lipstick or just blush,"
「なんか本当に下手くそだった思い出があるから…」「うん…」
"I have memories of being really clumsy with it..." "Yeah..."
「ちょっとね、そこは恥ずかしいなって感じだけど」
"So it feels a bit embarrassing, looking back."
「『チークのみ』はなかなか見んかもね」「え、そうだね」
"You don't often see 'blush only', that's true." "Yeah, right."
「結構知ってた。ロムアンドとかバッチリしてそうな感じ」
"I knew a decent amount. Rom&nd and stuff, felt like I did it properly."
「ラミはしてたね。なんか結構コスメ好きだったから」「おー！」
"Lamy did it. She really liked cosmetics." "Oh!"
「ま、別に誰に見られるわけでもなく…」「うん」
"Well, not like I had anyone specific seeing me..." "Yeah."
「スクールメイクしてましたね」「えー、なんか…」
"I did school makeup." "Woah, like..."
「コツというかさ、スクールだったからこそみたいなのやり方とかあった？」
"Were there any tips or tricks specifically because it was school makeup?"
「学生時代の…」
"From student days..."
「あ、でも、やっぱアイラインめっちゃ濃く引いちゃうとさ、バレちゃうじゃん？」
"Ah, but if you draw your eyeliner really thick, you'll get caught, right?"
「あ、たしかに。あ、バレないようにやってたんだ」「そうそう」
"Ah, true. Ah, so you did it so you wouldn't get caught." "Exactly."
「一応ね。一応バレないようにというか、薄めに」「うんうん」
"Just in case. Just in case, to not get caught, keeping it thin." "Yeah yeah."
でもなんか結構色々、眉とかも整えてたし
But you know, they kept everything neat, even their eyebrows.
あー確かに 眉毛整っ...
Ah, true, eyebrows trimmed...
眉ね 大事！
Eyebrows, yeah! Very important!
大事！ 大事だよね。
Important! It really is important.
そう、眉毛はね、顔の印象だいぶ変わりますから。
Right, eyebrows really change the impression of your face.
うんうん、だからだいぶナチュラルメイク、キャンメイクとかも使ってたよ。
Yeah, so it was pretty natural makeup. She even used CANMAKE,
あのプチプラの。
that budget brand!
キャンメイクですよ、やっぱ！
It's CANMAKE, as expected!
神だよね！ 神だね！
It's a godsend. Totally a godsend!
キャンメイク今も使ってて、結構。
I still use CANMAKE a lot even now.
うん、可愛いしね、パケがね。そう、可愛い、安い。
Yeah, and the packaging is cute! Right, cute and cheap.
しかも結構質が高いと思っている。
Plus, I think the quality is actually pretty high.
めっちゃいい！ なんかその、この価格だけどチークの塗りとかもすごい綺麗に出るし。
It's so good! Like, at that price, even the blush goes on and shows up so nicely.
そうそう、なんかね、コスメすごい好きなお友達がいるんですけど。
Yeah, yeah! I have a friend who absolutely loves cosmetics,
その子もキャンメイク結構取り入れてて。
and even she incorporates CANMAKE quite a bit.
なんか高いお金に固執しなくても全然素敵なメイクできるなっておすすめしたかったです。
It made me want to recommend it, showing you don't have to stick to expensive stuff to do great makeup.
あーそうだね。おすすめだね。
Ah, that's true! Highly recommended.
てか今ね、結構100均とかでもさ、メイクグッズって売ってるじゃないですか。
By the way, these days, 100-yen stores sell makeup items too, right?
確かに、ある！
True, they do!
あれもなんか、結構普通に使えるのよ。
Those are actually pretty usable too!
え、そうなんだ！ 使ったことなかった。おすすめとかある？
Eh, really? I've never used them. Do you have any recommendations?
あ、でもアイライナーとかは全然発色もいいし、落ちにくいし。
Ah, but the eyeliners have great color payoff and don't smudge easily.
あ、そうなんだ！ すごーい！
Oh, really? Wow!
そう、全然使えるよ！ めっちゃいいよ！
Yeah, they're totally usable! Really good!
ね、学生だとやっぱね、高いからね、メイク道具もね。
Right, when you're a student, makeup items are expensive.
しかも月1ぐらいの感じになるじゃん、1個ずつ。
Plus, buying them one by one feels like a monthly expense.
とするとやっぱ100均嬉しいよな。
So 100-yen stores are a real lifesaver.
100均、手軽に試せるね。
With 100-yen items, you can try them easily.
うんうん、ぜひ参考にしてみてください！
Yeah, yeah! Please give them a try as reference!
はーい！
Okay!
はい、では次ちょっと男子から行ってみましょうかね。
Alright, next let's move on to one from a guy.
「美女3人のフェチが知りたいです！」
"I'd like to know the fetishes of you three beauties!"
うわー！ フェチ！ フェチ！
Whoa! Fetishes! Fetishes!
フェチか。何フェチ？ ある？
Fetishes, huh? What fetishes do you have? Any?
今ちょっと考えてる。でもね、ラミィ結構ね、やっぱちょっと汗の匂いかもしれないな。
I'm thinking right now. But you know, Lamy might actually be into the smell of sweat.
あー！ 匂い！ 言ってた！
Ah! Smell! You mentioned that before!
そう、ちょっとやっぱみんな、今さ、露出が激しいじゃないですか、季節柄。
Yeah, everyone's showing a lot of skin right now, given the season.
いやでも、なんかちょっと汗かいてそうなところの匂い嗅ぎたいもんね。
But still, you just want to smell places that look like they're sweating, right?
えー！ 嗅がせたくない！
EH?! I don't want you smelling me!
え、嗅がせたくないよ！ 汗は汗やで！
Eh, I don't wanna let you smell! Sweat is sweat!
そうだ。これ前にも、もしかしたら取り扱ったかもしれない。
Right. We might have talked about this before.
こよりは声。そうですね、その時も言ってた気がしますね。
Koyori is voice. Right, I think I said that back then too.
あ、声なんだ！ 声。やっぱ声優さんとか好きだったから、子供の頃から。
Ah, voice! Voice. Yeah, I've loved voice actors since I was a kid.
あ、この人の声こんな感じなんだな、みたいなのちょっとまず気にしちゃうところがありますね。
So I always first pay attention to like, "Ah, so this person's voice sounds like this."
さあ、ノエル先輩。
Now then, Noel-senpai.
ノエちゃん？ ノエたん！ ノエたんは、
Noe-chan? Noe-tan! Noe-tan is...
そう、手かも。手！
Right, hands, maybe. Hands!
どういう手がいいかというと、むちむちな手が好き！
As for what kind of hands, I like chubby, plump hands!
赤ちゃんみたいな手が好き。
I like hands that look like baby hands.
へー！ 意外！
Ehh! How unexpected!
なんか触ったら気持ちよさそうとかそういう感じ？
Like, they feel good to touch, or something like that?
もそうだし、見た目的にも可愛いなと思って。
That too, plus visually I just think they look so cute.
で、なんかやっぱさ、手とかって骨格なのかな。
And you know, hand shape—maybe it's about the bone structure?
見た目的には全然細いのに、手だけちょっとむちむちしてる女の子とかいるじゃん。
Like, even if a girl is super slender overall, there are girls whose hands are plump, right?
確かに！ 確かに！
True! True!
そう、そういう子に憧れるんだよね。団長とか…
Yeah, I admire girls like that. Dancho, for instance...
まぁ今画面には映ってないけど、手が結構やっぱり、
Well, it's not showing on screen right now, but my hands are pretty...
骨がちょっと角張ってるんだよね。これがちょっとコンプレックスで。
the bones are a bit angular, you know? That's a bit of a complex for me.
え、そうなんだ。丸みがあるお手手はずっと憧れてるの。
Eh, really? So I've always admired round, chubby hands.
へー！ 知らなかった！
Ehh! I didn't know that!
クリームパンみたいな手とかもう大好き。握りたくなるかもね。
I absolutely love hands that look like cream buns. Makes you want to hold them.
そう！ なるほど！
Exactly! I see!
なんか今コメント欄に「吉良吉影」って言われてて…
Someone in the comments just said "Yoshikage Kira"...
いやいや、そんな！ 切ったりそこまでは！
No, no! Not like cutting them off or anything like that!
ちょっと気になっちゃうなというところですかね。
So it's just something I end up paying attention to.
そうですね、フェチです。
Right, that's my fetish.
なるほど。ではもう1個ちょっと、ノエル先輩に聞きたい、我々前回話してるやつなんですけど、ノエたんね！
I see. Now, there's one more question I'd like to ask Noel-senpai—one that we talked about last time. Right, Noe-tan!
はい、こちらです。「相手に対して冷める瞬間があるとしたら、どんな瞬間ですか？よろしくお願いします」とのこと。
"If there's a moment where you get turned off by someone, what kind of moment would it be? Please answer!"
あー！聞きたいですね！ 聞きたい！
"Ah, I want to hear this!" "Me too!"
冷めるというか...前回は100年の恋も冷めるみたいなのって何？みたいな話をしていて...
"Getting turned off... Last time, we talked about what makes even a hundred years of love turn cold..."
こよりは店員さんに怒っちゃうとか... 話してたね！
"Koyori mentioned getting angry at store clerks..." "Yeah, we were talking about that!"
それはもちろん知っておりますよ！ 見てくださってありがとうございます！
"Of course I know about that!" "Thank you for watching!"
なにかありますか？ 配信を見ながら「自分だったら何だろう」ってちょっと思ってたんだけど...
"Is there anything for you?" "While watching that stream, I was wondering what it would be for me..."
なんか...そうだなぁ、嘘...嘘かな？嘘つくときとか...
"Well... let's see, lies... lies maybe? When someone lies..."
でも嘘もさ、色んな嘘があるじゃない？
"But there are all kinds of lies, right?"
優しい嘘なら良いと思うんだけど、見栄を張るような嘘だと冷めちゃうかも。
"A gentle lie is fine, but a lie told to show off might turn me off."
え！見栄を張るような嘘って例えば、「俺、年収5000億ある」とか？
"A lie to show off... like, 'I have an annual income of 500 billion'?"
それはギャグだから良いんだけど... 5000億はね...
"That's a joke, so it's fine... 500 billion is..."
5000億はね...自分を良く見せようっていうのは、背伸びしたくらいだったら良いかもだけど、ちょっと嫌かもな...
"Trying to make yourself look good, stretching the truth a bit might be okay, but it's a bit unpleasant..."
嘘でやってね、みたいな... 多分ね、団長はね...
"Telling lies to do that..." "I think for Danchou..."
弱いところが見たい。
"She wants to see their weak side."
嘘をついてまで強くいようっていうのはちょっと嫌だな〜って。 本当のところを見せてほしいんだね。
"Trying to be tough by telling lies is distasteful. You want them to show their real side."
団長ね、幼児化したおじさんが好きだからね！ すごいピンポイントだな！
"Danchou likes middle-aged men who act like toddlers!" "That's super specific!"
幼児化したおじさんが好き... 幼児も好きだもんね！ そう！
"Middle-aged men acting like toddlers..." "You like toddlers too!" "Right!"
キャラクターでいう...幼児も好き... すり替わりのノエルだと思ったんですけど
"As far as characters go... I like toddlers too..." "I thought it was the swapped Noel..."
やっぱり『バキ』のドリアンっていうキャラがいるんだけど、その人がね、幼児化したおじいちゃん...
"In 'Baki', there's a character named Dorian, and he's an old man who acts like an infant..."
そう！それが本当にタイプで...嘘ついてほしくないな...ありのままで...
"Yeah! That's really my type... I don't want them to lie... Just as they are..."
ちょっと調べたんだけど、幼児化してキャンディ求める... マッチョのね、キャンディが...
"I looked it up, he regresses to an infant and asks for candy... A muscular guy asking for candy..."
かわいいんだよ！ 「キャンディキャンディ」ってコメント欄で書かれてる...
"It's so cute!" "'Candy candy' is being written in the comments..."
キャンディおじさんだからね！ 「キャンディとかいらねぇし」とか言わないでほしいっていうことですかね！
"Because he's the candy old man!" "So you mean you don't want them saying 'I don't need candy'?"
強がらないで本当はキャンディが欲しいのに「甘いもん食えねぇし」とか言わないでほしい。
"Without acting tough, if they want candy, I don't want them saying 'I can't eat sweet stuff'."
ありのままでいようね！甘えさせてください！ 分かるわ〜。嘘は嫌だよね。
"Let me be as I am! Let us spoil you!" "I get it. Lies are awful."
ノエルちゃんに甘えられるの最高やんけ！ 幼児化していいならする... するけど...
"Getting spoiled by Noel-chan is the best!" "If I can regress to a toddler, I will..." "You will?"
いいんですか？しかもそれで愛してもらえるの最高すぎるの！ お世話したい！
"Is that okay? And being loved for it is awesome!" "I want to take care of you!"
え、じゃあちょっと...「正直、下ネタ言う男子はモテませんか？」という...
"Well then... 'Honestly, do guys who tell dirty jokes not get popular?'"
どのレベルの？ そこは想像と...「ここまでならOK」とか聞きたいんですけど...
"What level of jokes?" "I want to know where the line is..."
下ネタ言う男子... 「ねね」ぐらいのだったら全然気にならないけど...
"Guys who tell dirty jokes..." "If it's around Nene's level, I don't mind at all..."
小学生男子みたいなのね！ そうそうそう！ 良いかも。
"Like elementary school boys!" "Exactly!" "That might be okay."
モテるかモテないかで考えると、どう思いますか？
"Thinking about whether they're popular or not, what do you think?"
モテないんじゃない？ 分かる
"Probably not popular?" "I agree."
品格の問題じゃない？女の子の前でわざわざ下ネタを言わなくても良くないか？ってなる。
"Isn't it a matter of decency? You don't need to force dirty jokes in front of girls."
そうだよね。やっぱりそういう話って関係性が大事で...そこまでの関係性に行ってるってことは...
"Right. For that kind of talk, the relationship matters... If you're already that close..."
もう下ネタ抜きでモテてる気がするから...下ネタでモテるってことはなさそう。
"You're already popular without dirty jokes... Nobody gets popular because of them."
逆説ね！ 「下ネタ言ったからモテる」は、ない！ ない！
"Exactly!" "'Getting popular because of dirty jokes' doesn't exist!" "It doesn't!"
なんか友達止まりになっちゃいそうな感じがする...
It feels like they'd just end up staying as friends...
好きな男の子が下ネタめっちゃ言ってたら、でもちょっとやっぱ嫌だな。
Though if a guy I liked said a ton of dirty jokes, I think I'd actually dislike it.
あー、確かに。
Ah, that's true.
ちょっと幻滅することもあるかもね。下ネタの質と内容によっては。
You might get a bit turned off, depending on the nature and content of the dirty jokes.
でもこの質問が来るってことは、言いながらモテたいってことなのかな？
But the fact that this question was sent... does it mean he wants to say them and still be popular?
「俺は下ネタを言いたいんだ！」
"I want to tell dirty jokes!"
言っちゃうみたいな欲望。「でもそれでモテたら嬉しいな」みたいな。
That urge to say them... like, "But it'd be great if I was still popular."
言っちゃうタイプだから、このまま生きてモテるならこのまま生きる。これでモテないならやめようかな、みたいな。
He's the type to say them, so he's like, "If I can be popular like this, I will. But if I can't, maybe I'll stop."
いや、これちょっとデカいぞ！この子が今後モテるかモテないか、ちょっと左右するかもしれない！
Whoa, this is actually pretty big! This might affect whether he becomes popular or not!
はっきり言っとかないと！下ネタ、たぶんモテないぞ！
We have to say it clearly! Dirty jokes probably won't make you popular!
そうだね。モテる要素がないかもね。
That's true. There's really no element there that makes you popular.
確かに。モテたいならちょっと控えた方が... 男子だけの場とかで言って発散したらいいんじゃないですかね。
True. If you want to be popular, hold back a bit... maybe just let it out when it's just guys.
それができるのは...
If you can do that...
ていうか、全然関係ない話していい？
Wait, can I talk about something completely unrelated?
あのさ、この間友達とご飯に行ったんですよ。
So the other day, I went out to eat with a friend.
そしたら、後ろにいた男の子の4人組ぐらいがいたんですけど...
And there was a group of about four guys sitting behind us...
エグい下ネタ言ってて！
Saying super crazy dirty jokes!
もうずーっと、最初から最後まで下ネタ言ってて！
Like, the whole time! From beginning to end, they were telling dirty jokes!
マジか... ま、でも、こっちまで聞こえちゃうのはあれだけど...
Seriously... Well, hearing it from over here is a bit much...
でも、男子だけで盛り上がってるのはね...
But when it's just guys getting hyped up...
男子ってやっぱそういうものなのかな？我々は知らないじゃん。男子だけの集まりを。
Are guys really just like that? We don't know what it's like when it's just guys.
みんなそうなの？
Is everyone like that?
聞きあげたい！コメントのみんなにね。
I want to ask everyone in the comments!
でも「TPOを弁えてくれ」って言ってる人もいるから...
But some people are saying "Keep TPO in mind"...
声の大きさが大事ね。
The volume of your voice is important.
聞こえてきちゃったんだもん、だって！
Because we could hear it, after all!
そっちはね、そっちのボリュームの問題だからね。
Well, that's an issue with their volume.
人による、言わないよ... あ、「学生はそうかも」だって。
"Depends on the person," "I don't say that"... Ah, "Maybe students are like that."
あー、でもそう、学生さんっぽかった！ちょっと。
Ah, but yeah, they did seem a bit like students!
赤からのイタリアンね。ちょっと思春期なのかもだね。
An Italian place after Akakara. Maybe they're still in adolescence.
そうですね。でもこより結構聞いちゃうかも。
Right. But Koyori, you ended up listening pretty closely.
「そういう話するんだ！」って。
Like, "So they do talk about that!"
気になっちゃうよね。ずっと女子校だったからさ、分かんないの、本当に。学生の男の子たちが何を考えてるのか。
You can't help but be curious. Since I went to an all-girls school, I really don't know what student guys think about.
分析しちゃうんだ！なるほど。
So you end up analyzing it! I see.
ちなみにノエちゃんは、共学？女子校？どっちでしたっけ？
By the way, Noel-chan... was your school co-ed or all-girls? Which was it?
えっとね、高校まで共学で、大学で女子大だった。
Well, co-ed up through high school, and an all-women's university.
へえー！結構珍しいタイプ！じゃあ男女両方の目線を知ってるみたいな...
Woah! That's a pretty rare pattern! So you know both perspectives...
そうですね。一応理解はするけれども、男子も気になるね。
That's right. I do understand to an extent, but I'm curious about guys too.
聞いていちゃいますね！
You end up overhearing it!
はい。ではそんな共学と女子高な3人ですが...
Alright then. For the three of us from co-ed and all-girls schools...
こちら！
Here's this!
3人に恋愛の2択についてお聞きしたいです。好きな人（恋愛対象）に刺激と安心どちらを求めますか？
"I'd like to ask you three about a 2-choice romance question. When it comes to someone you like, do you seek excitement or reassurance?"
思わせぶりな言動などで毎回ドキドキさせてくる方か、一緒にいて落ち着く素でいられる方、どちらを重視されるでしょうか？
"Someone who makes your heart race with flirtatious behavior every time, or someone you can be relaxed and natural around—which do you value more?"
私は安心タイプで、好きな気持ちは伝えられるのですが、ドラマのようにドキドキさせる言動は恥ずかしくてできません。女の子はどちらが嬉しいですか？
"I'm the reassurance type, so I can convey my feelings, but flirtatious, heart-racing gestures like in dramas are embarrassing and hard to do. Which one makes girls happier?"
ということで、せーので「刺激」か「安心」か、どちらか答えてみたいと思います。
So, let's answer on the count of three with either "Excitement" or "Reassurance."
せーの！
Ready, set...
安心！
Reassurance!
おー！揃った！
Woah! We matched!
揃ったねー！安心が... ここは揃いましたね！乙女心を知ったか！
We matched! Reassurance... We all agreed on this! Seems like we understand a maiden's heart!
あ、ラミ？刺激って... 今書いてある「思わせぶりな言動で毎回ドキドキさせてくる」って書いてあるけど...
Ah, Lamy? Excitement... It says here, "making your heart race with flirtatious behavior every time," but...
そんな思わせぶりな言動されたら、何？困るんだけど。
If someone acted so flirtatious with me, I'd just be confused.
え、それ何？どういう意味？ラミのこと好きじゃないってこと？どういうこと？なんでそんなことすんの？
What does that mean? Does it mean you don't actually like me? What is it? Why would you do that?
そうだね。絶対安心の方がいいな。
That's true. Reassurance is definitely better.
ノエちゃんはどうですか？
Noel-chan, how about you?
いや、なんか人生って、生きるって大変やん。それなのに刺激なんて要らんです。
Man, living life is hard enough as it is. We don't need extra excitement on top of that.
安心が欲しい。やばい、優しさが欲しいでやんすよ。
I want reassurance. Man, I just want kindness.
分かるわ、めちゃくちゃ。
I get that so much.
なんか、ずっと一緒にいるっていう前提で考えたくて...
Like, I want to think about it on the premise of being together forever...
この恋愛というものを...
When thinking about romance...
あ、何？それ、それは24時間一緒にいるとか、どういうこと？
Huh, what? Does that mean being together 24 hours a day, or what?
っていうか、もう何だろう...
I mean, how should I put it...
付き合って本当、行けるならゴール、その結婚、そして生涯最後までみたいなぐらいの...
If you start dating, aiming for the goal line of marriage, and staying together until the very end of your lives...
墓までね。そうそう、墓までみたいな...
Right, until the grave. Yeah, thinking about going all the way to the grave...
ことを考えて、恋愛というものを考えたときに...
When I think about romance in those terms...
うん、安心がもう、大事すぎない？
Isn't feeling a sense of security the most important thing?
ずっと癒やされてね、安心感して、こう...なんか、ホッとする...
Always feeling comforted, secure, and... like, relieved...
家庭でありたいと思うから...
Because I want us to be like a home...
そう、だから、なんか...別に刺激要らんなってなる...
Yeah, so I end up feeling like I don't really need excitement.
うん。まあそうだね、長く一緒にいること考えたら...
Well, yeah. If you think about being together for a long time...
刺激って逆にちょっと...困るかもな。
Constant excitement might actually become a bit troublesome.
しかもさ、刺激を求めるってことは、刺激ってさ、なんか慣れてくじゃんか。あー、確かに。
Besides, seeking excitement means... well, you get used to excitement after a while, right? Ah, true.
いろんな絡みだったり、そう。だからこの場合の刺激っつーのは...
Like getting involved in all kinds of things... Yeah. So the excitement in that case...
最終的にどこまで行くの？
Where does it ultimately end up going?
なんかちょっと怖いね！確かに！
That's kind of scary! True!
そう、長く見たときに、なんか...ちょっとした刺激じゃもう、全然反応もしないみたいになっちゃいそう。
Yeah, over a long period, it feels like minor excitement won't even elicit a response anymore.
SMに発展していってしまう...
It might escalate into SM territory...
大丈夫？そっちに行く？
Are you okay? Is that where you're heading?
まあなんか、刺激とか最初の3回ぐらいまででいいんじゃないかなみたいな...
Well, I feel like having excitement just for the first three times or so is enough...
感じよね。付き合う前とかに、そういうドキドキ感があればいいんじゃない？
Right? As long as there's that thrilling feeling before you start dating, isn't that fine?
勝手にドキドキするだろうしね。
You'll naturally feel nervous/excited on your own anyway.
いや勝手にやめて！一人でにね！
Hey, stop doing it on your own! All by yourself!
はい、ということで、まあたぶん分からないですけど、多くの女の子は安心なんじゃないかなという...
Alright then! I don't know for sure, but I think most girls probably prefer security.
はい。そうですね。
Yes. That's true.
ちょっと恋愛とはまた別のところなんですけれども...
Now, moving slightly away from dating topics...
脱毛しようか迷っています。（男性）
"I'm contemplating getting hair removal done. (Male)."
しろ！
Do it!
早い！早い！
That was fast! So fast!
女性から見て、毛があるのとないのとでは結構印象変わってくるのでしょうか？
"From a woman's perspective, does having or not having body hair significantly change the impression?"
え、しろなの？！
Wait, your answer is "Do it"?!
え、もう絶対ヒゲ脱毛とかしたほうが良くない？だって...
Isn't it definitely better to get beard removal done? Because...
いや、なんかさ、毎朝毎朝さ、剃ってるんでしょ？
I mean, they shave every single morning, right?
まあ確かに。うんうんうん。
Well, true. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
だし、なんこういう、刃がさ、やっぱ肌に当たると刺激になってさ、そこが荒れちゃったりとかするわけじゃないですか。
And when the blade touches the skin, it causes irritation, which can break out their skin, right?
あ、そうなんだ。痛いしね。
Oh, I see. And it hurts.
そういうの考えると、もう絶対ヒゲ脱毛なんて、ラミィが男性だったら、まず真っ先にやる！
Considering all that, if Lamy were a guy, beard hair removal is the very first thing I'd do!
確かに！
That's true!
生やしたい人は別にそのまま生やしてくださいだけど、剃ってる人はね。
If someone wants to grow out a beard, they can just leave it, but for those who shave...
うんうん。楽になると思うけど。
Yeah, I think it makes life much easier.
団長はそこまでって感じ？
Are you not as fussed about it, Danchou?
なんか、団長はあんまり...その...
Well, Danchou doesn't really... um...
ラミィはその人のこと思っていってくれているじゃんか。「あ、そう視点があるんだ」って思ったけど...
Lamy spoke with consideration for the person, making me realize "Oh, that's a good perspective," but...
団長はちょっとね、自分の好みで言うと...
Speaking from Danchou's personal preference...
なんか本当にどっちでもよくて...
I honestly don't mind either way...
なんかさ、毛があったときにね...
Like, when someone has body hair...
毛ってさ、意味があるところに入るわけじゃん。
Hair grows in places where there's a purpose for it, right?
体毛が濃い人は、その分体を守らなきゃいけないのかなと思って...
So if someone has thick body hair, I feel like maybe their body needs extra protection...
ほう！ストーリーなんだね！
Oh! You look at it like a story!
なんかすごいクマさんみたいだなという感じで...
I feel like, "Oh, they're like a fluffy bear..."
クマさん可愛いなって。
And I think bears are cute.
いや、でも、本当に脱毛しようかしないかで言うならば、脱毛しようか迷ってんだったらした方がいいと思う。
Well, if you're undecided on getting hair removal, I think you should just do it if you're leaning towards it.
あー、確かに。
Ah, true.
女子から見て毛があった方がいいとかない方がいいとかは、人それぞれだと思うけど...
Whether women prefer hair or no hair varies from person to person, but...
やっぱ自分自身だと思うな。しかも脱毛って痛い！
Ultimately it comes down to how you feel about yourself. Plus, hair removal hurts!
そうだね、お金もかかりますし。
That's true, and it costs money too.
周りからどう見られるかよりも、自分自身が...
Rather than worrying about how others see you, your own...
やって、なんかこう過ごしやすいかでやった方が後悔もないと思うので。
doing it based on whether it makes your daily life easier will leave you with no regrets.
確かに。そうかも。
True. That might be so.
まあね、そういう感じで団長は...
Well, so that's how Danchou feels about it...
毛がある人を見て「毛があるな、嫌だな」って思うことはないよね。
I never look at a guy with hair and think, "Ugh, he has hair, I dislike it."
そうだね、そんな毛深い人を見たことがない...
Yeah, I haven't really seen anyone particularly hairy...
すれ違う人くらいしかないから、そこで考えることそんなないけど...
Other than people I pass by on the street, so I don't think about it much, but...
脱毛したからいいとか、してないからいいとか、そういう印象の変化はないのかなみたいな...
I don't think getting hair removal changes my impression of someone positively or negatively.
あ、剃る人なんだな、そのままの人なんだな、それだけって感じがする。
It's just "Oh, they shave," or "Oh, they keep it natural." That's all it feels like to me.
うん、なんか本当にスタイルだよね。その人の生き様というか...
Yeah, it's really just personal style and how a person chooses to live.
うん、うん、うん
Mm-hmm, yeah.
なことあんまり気にしたことないね。
I've never really paid much attention to that.
うん。
Yeah.
まあでもなんかヒゲを脱毛したいと迷ってるなら...
Well, but if you're undecided about getting beard removal...
...したほうがいいっていうラミたんの熱い...
...Lamy-tan's passionate advice is that you should.
絶対だって困ってるそうだもんね、きっとその...
Because they must be troubled by it, like...
やっぱ毎回剃ったりとかね。
having to shave every time,
肌荒れしたりとか。
or getting skin irritation.
圧倒的に自分がやっぱ脱毛して良かったと感じているから...
Since she overwhelmingly feels glad she got hair removal herself...
あー、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
ていうのもあるかな。
...there's that too.
楽ちんとかね。
Like how convenient it is.
うん、確かにね。
Yeah, that's true.
楽ちんではあるな。
It certainly is convenient.
ね。
Right.
意外とね、すごい痛いところとか麻酔とかやれるしね。
Surprisingly, for really painful areas, you can use anesthesia and all.
顔はどうなんだろ？ヒゲってどうなんだろう？分からないけど...
How is it for the face? What about beards? I don't know, but...
分からないけど...
I'm not sure, but...
どうなんでしょうか。調べてみてもいいのではないかと...
How is it? I think it might be worth looking into...
思います。はい。
...I reckon. Yes.
さあ、では続きまして...
Now then, moving on...
ちょっと変の行ってもいいですか？
Can I move to a slightly weird one?
お、いいよー。
Oh, sure!
夜も更けてまいりましたので...
Since it's getting late into the night...
お風呂で異性に洗わせてもいい場所の限界を教えてください、という...
"Please tell us the limit of places you'd let someone of the opposite sex wash in the bath"...
謎のマシュマロが...
...what a mysterious Marshmallow question!
何それ！
What is that?!
え、限界？！
Huh, limit?!
誰、この異性って？
Who is this "opposite sex"?
何の異性なの？
What kind of person are they?
そうなの。なんか、え、店？
Yeah, like, huh? A salon? A shop?
彼女？どっち？！
A girlfriend? Which is it?!
誰なの？！異性って誰なの？！
Who is it?! Who is this opposite sex?!
分かんないけど...
I don't know, but...
こよは、彼女なのだとしたら...
If Koyori was the girlfriend...
彼女が洗いたいならどこまででもいいんじゃないって思った。
I thought if the girlfriend wants to wash, anywhere should be fine.
結果... どういうこと？
Wait... what do you mean by that?
こよが彼女だったら、ラミはどこも洗ってもいいってこと？
If Koyo was the girlfriend, does that mean Lamy could wash anywhere?
あ、違う違う！え、何？ラミたんが洗ってくれんの？
Ah, no no! Wait, what? Lamy-tan would wash for them?
待って、話が変わってくるんだけど、そこ！
Wait, the premise is completely changing here!
え、なんか、どっちだろう？
Um, like, which one is it?
こよが彼女で... こよが彼女だとちょっと難しいな...
Koyo being the girlfriend... wait, Koyo as the girlfriend is a bit confusing...
彼女が「えっ、君の全部洗ってあげたいの」って言ってきて...
If the girlfriend says, "I want to wash all of you,"...
自分もまんざらでもないなら、全部洗わせていいんじゃない？
and you don't mind either, shouldn't you let her wash everything?
あー... あ、このマシュマロの人になりきってんの今？
Ah... Are you roleplaying as the person who sent the Marshmallow right now?
あ、そうそうそう！なりきった上で！
Ah, yes yes yes! From that perspective!
そういうことか！
I get it now!
でも多分このマシュマロの人は、団長たちが異性が洗うならどこまで許せるかっていう話だと思って聞いてたから...
But I thought this Marshmallow sender was asking how far we'd allow someone of the opposite sex to wash us...
じゃあ「洗ってほしいな」って言う側、言われる側...
So the side asking "I want you to wash me" versus the person being asked...
洗ってほしいな...
"I want you to wash me"...
洗ってほしいなって言われる側？
The side being asked to wash them?
この子が彼女に対して「洗ってほしいな」って言いたいの申しれないかな...
Maybe this person wants to tell their girlfriend, "I want you to wash me"...
そうしたら「どこまで求めていいですか？」っていうことにする？じゃあ。
So should we treat it as, "How far am I allowed to request?" then?
ムズい...
This is confusing...
どういうこと？どういうこと？
What do you mean? What do you mean?
なんか自分の立ち位置が分からん... 自分誰？！
I don't know where I stand here... Who am I?!
この子の彼女だとして！このマシュマロ主の彼女だとして！
Imagine you're this person's girlfriend! This Marshmallow sender's girlfriend!
で、マシュマロ主であるこの彼氏君が一緒に風呂に入ろうってことになりました。
And this boyfriend, the Marshmallow sender, ends up taking a bath with you.
で、この彼氏君は洗ってほしいっぽい、自分の体を。
And this boyfriend seems to want his body washed.
ああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
そうそうそう。「ちょっと洗いっこしようよ」みたいなときに...
Right right right. When he's like, "Let's wash each other,"...
どこまでだったらラインを超えないのか。
...how far can it go without crossing the line?
すごいな、もうライン超えてると思うんだけど！
Wow, I feel like the line is already crossed!
あ、超えてるか！
Ah, it's already crossed?!
いや、もうお風呂入ってんならもう...
I mean, if you're already in the bath together...
もう関係ない！ない、そんなん！
...it doesn't matter anymore! There is no line!
あ、そうかー。
Ah, really?
でも普通だったら背中までよなって思ったりね。
But normally you'd think up to the back, right?
あー、なるほど。背中を流す？
Ah, I see. Scrubbing the back?
背中の洗いっこ... までなのかな。
Washing each other's back... maybe up to there.
でもラミがこよの身体洗ってもいいんだったらどこまででも洗いますよ！
But if Lamy is allowed to wash Koyori's body, I'll wash anywhere!
うそー！
No way!
え、どこまででも？！
Wait, anywhere?!
ノエルたんもノエルたんもどこまででも洗うよ！
Noel-tan too, Noel-tan too, I'll wash anywhere!
ほんまに？！
Really?!
洗うけど？
I would, though?
僕が男だったらどこまで洗ってくれんの？じゃあ... お願いします！
If I were a guy, how far would you wash for me? Well then... please!
でもさ、ラミ、団長の身体洗ってくれるって...
Wait, but Lamy saying she'd wash Dancho's body...
うん！
Yeah!
言うけど、ちょっとややこしいよ、身体洗うルーティンが。
...she says that, but my body washing routine is a bit complicated.
ラミたんも多分美容にいろいろやってるから、ちょっと細かいかもしれんけど...
Lamy-tan probably does a lot for beauty care too, so it might be detailed, but...
あ、いいよ、覚える覚える！
Ah, fine, I'll learn it, I'll learn it!
まず泡立てるじゃん。
First, you lather it up, right?
で、身体洗うけど、大事な... あるじゃんね？その下の、大事なところは... 泡石鹸で洗ってほしい！
And you wash the body, but the sensitive... you know, right? Down there, the sensitive areas... I want them washed with foam soap!
めっちゃ指定してるから！
You're giving such specific instructions!
ラミィも別の石鹸で洗ってる！
Lamy also washes with a different soap!
洗ってるでしょ！
You wash with it, right!
そういうのをちゃんとやってくれるならいいね。
If she does all that properly for you, that's great.
ラミィね。
Lamy, right?
なるほどね。わかったわかった。全部覚えるわ。
I see. Okay, okay. I'll remember everything.
1から全部覚えるから、洗わせてもらっていい？
I'll remember everything from top to bottom, so can I wash you?
それならいいかなー。うんうん。オッケーオッケー、任せるわ。
If it's that, then maybe it's fine~ Yeah, yeah. Okay, okay, I'll leave it to you.
またラミィちゃん...この番組やるとラミィちゃんが良い女であることがどんどんね、世間にバレていくだけの...
Again, Lamy-chan... when we do this show, Lamy-chan being a good woman just keeps getting exposed to the public...
有難い！
Thank you!
自覚...
Self-awareness...
いや、もうこよも言っていってね。何がどうとかね、全部覚えるんで。
No, Koyo should say it too. Like what is how, I'll remember it all.
こよはあんまり特にないから、ラミィちゃんがやってるやつをやってもらった方が綺麗になりそう。
Koyo doesn't really have much, so doing what Lamy-chan does would probably make me cleaner.
あ、なるほどなるほど。分かった、任せろ。
Ah, I see, I see. Got it, leave it to me.
お任せします！
I'll leave it to you!
でも今の分かったのは、女の子の体を洗いたいんだったら、女の子結構ね、その色々気にしてることあるかな？そこを気遣ってあげるといいんじゃないかっていう感じですかね？
But what we learned just now is, if you want to wash a girl's body, girls have various things they're self-conscious about, so being considerate of that might be good, right?
そうだね！
That's right!
それができたら120点だね。
If you can do that, it's 120 points.
120点ですね！面白かったんでちょっとやっちゃいました、すいません。
120 points! It was fun so I went a bit far, sorry.
じゃあ、ちょっとね、ノエルっちゃんだからこその、恋愛相談モードに入りたいと思います！
Then, let me enter romance consultation mode precisely because Noel-chan is here!
はい！
Yes!
恋愛相談の一発目をご紹介いたしましょう！
Let me introduce the first romance consultation!
はい！
Yes!
団長がいるということでご相談させてください！
Since the Captain is here, please allow me to consult!
今自分にはおっぱいのおっきい彼女がいます。
"Right now, I have a girlfriend with big breasts."
おー！
Ooh!
そして何を隠そう自分は大のおっぱい星人であります！
"And truth be told, I am a huge boob fanatic!"
おー！
Ooh!
ウィンウィンじゃん！
That's a win-win!
ウィンウィンなんですけど、彼女にはカッコいいところだけを見せたく、そのことについては言っておらず、
"It's a win-win, but I only want to show my cool side to my girlfriend, so I haven't mentioned it to her..."
「べ、別に興味ねえし」みたいな態度をとってしまいます。
"...and I act like 'I-It's not like I care.'"
あ、なんかちょっとさっきのキャンディにちょっと繋がる感じだけど。
Ah, that kind of connects to the candy topic earlier.
このまま我慢してカッコいい自分を見せ続けるか、それとも引かれることを前提にありのまま自分をさらけ出すのがいいか、どっちがいいでしょうか？おっぱいぷるんぷるんだそうです。
"Should I keep enduring and showing my cool self, or should I reveal my true self assuming she might be turned off? Which is better? Boobs are bouncy bouncy, apparently."
これはでもノエたん決まってるでしょ、答え。
Well Noel-tan, the answer is pretty much set for this, right?
いや、決まって...でも何ヶ月かとかね、関係すると思うけど、でもさ、やっぱさらけ出した方がいい！
Well, it's set... but how many months they've been together might affect it, but honestly, it's better to reveal it!
だって、いつまでそのカッコいい姿...最初だけだよ、本当に。バレる！
Because how long can you keep up that cool appearance... it's only at the beginning, really. It'll be exposed!
てか、なんならバレてると思う、もう！
Or rather, I think she already knows!
目線でバレるんじゃないかってコメントが...
There's a comment saying it's probably obvious from where he looks...
あー！どうですか？
Ah~! What do you think?
なんか感じることある？
Do you ever feel that?
いや...なんか団長感じないけど、その感じたそう、街中とか...
No... I don't really feel it, but like, in town or something...
え、なんかあるよね、そのさ...コメントとかでもさ、大胸筋が大きいと目線とか気にならないですか？みたいな。
Eh, like, there are comments like "when your bust is big, don't you notice people staring?" and stuff like that.
あ、気になったこと...ない。
Ah, being bothered by it... I haven't.
え！？ないの！？
Eh?! None?!
絶対コンビニの店員さんとか見ちゃいそうだけど！
I feel like convenience store clerks would definitely look!
ない...
No...
ラミィですら毎回会ったら見てるよ！
Even Lamy looks every time we meet!
それはそう！見ちゃうな、うん。
That's true! I end up looking too, yeah.
ふ〜ん、それ感じてないんか。
Hmm, so you don't notice it.
あんまりもしかしたらその...そういう感じないような子だったな...気づいてないかも知れんけど...
Maybe she's the type of girl who doesn't really notice... she might not realize it, but...
でもさ、ほら、ラミィとかね、こよちゃんも...あるからさ、感じたりする？街中で。
But, see, Lamy and Koyo-chan... also have them, so do you feel it in town?
街中...街中はない。
In town... in town, no.
ではないけど、でも「あ、今なんかちょっと目線下だな」って思うことは...
Not that, but I do sometimes think "Ah, his gaze went down a bit just now"...
あるかな？面と向かってね、話すタイミングとかがある...お店の人とかね。
Maybe? When talking face-to-face, like with shop staff...
いやー...
Man...
でもどうだろう？こよ的には、ちょっとおっぱい星人まで...うん、急に言って...
How about it? For Koyo, suddenly saying "I'm a boob alien"...
それで何かが起きてしまったらちょっと怖いなって...この子の気持ちになると。
If something bad happens because of that, it's a bit scary... putting myself in her shoes.
そうだね！いきなりはね！
Right! Suddenly is a bit...
いきなりだと「え？もしかして大胸筋...おっぱいが大きいから付き合ったのかな」とか思われちゃうかもだから...
Suddenly might make her think "Eh? Did he only date me because my breasts are big?" so...
怖いかも。
That might be scary.
確かに。本当に付き合ってどれくらいの期間なのかプラス...
True. Plus how long they've actually been dating...
あとはもうちょっと...徐々にだね、やっぱ徐々に...
And then a bit... gradually, yeah, gradually...
っていうなんか、褒める感じでなんか...難しいよな。
Like, complimenting her... it's tough, though.
いや、確かにな...難しい。
Yeah, true... it's tough.
一気に難しくなってきた！確かに！
It suddenly got difficult! True!
でも、カッコつけるのは...あれ、続かないと思うんだよね。
But playing it cool... I don't think that can last, you know?
そうだね！
That's true!
「べ、別に興味ねえし」は嘘になっちゃってるから。
Saying "I-It's not like I care" turns into a lie.
そうそう！嘘になっちゃう。もしそう言えるようなタイミングが来た時には...
Yeah yeah! It turns into a lie. If a timing comes where you can say it...
「君自身が好きなことは大前提におっぱいも大好きだよ」みたいな...
"Of course I love you for who you are, but I also love your boobs!"...
言ったことないわ！
There's no timing to say that!
まあでもなんか「べ、別に好き...」
Well, but saying something like "I-It's not like I like..."
だね 「し」っていう態度は
So, you don't need to treat it as...
なしで
...a prerequisite condition.
普通に付き合えばいいのかもね なんかその
It's fine to just stay in a normal relationship.
わざわざね「おっぱい星人です」って宣言することは
There's no need to go out of your way to declare, "I'm a boob alien."
なくていいから
You don't have to do that.
なんか そうね なんかちょっと
It feels like showing off a bit...
強がってるというかね クールぶってる？
...or playing it cool.
でも 団長だったら嬉しいけどね ちなみに
Though as Noel, I'd be happy if they said that to me.
「おっぱい星人」って？
Like, "You're a boob alien"?
「おっぱい星人」
"Boob alien."
確かに 褒められてる感じで うん 嬉しい
It feels like a compliment. I'd be happy!
ラミちゃんは？ 嬉しい？
What about Lamy-tan?
ラミちゃんね 立派な...
Lamy-tan has an impressive pair too.
え、「おっぱい星人」？
"Boob alien"?
「おっぱい星人」嬉しいよ！
I'd be happy if they were a boob alien!
「おっぱい星人だったら全然、お、ラミの胸に飛んでおいで」ってなるけど。
Like, "Come fly right into Lamy's chest!" or something.
あー、確かにね。
Ah, that makes sense.
この胸で、こう、繋ぎ止められるみたいなところもある？なんか...
Like trapping them with your chest...
そんなの、ないけど...
What? No, that's not a thing!
え、ないか、ないか。なんかさ、その...
There's no such thing! What are you talking about?!
え、おっぱい、その、今付き合ってるってことじゃん。
Well, you're dating right now, right?
付き合ってるうえで、え、おっぱいまで好きだな、え、もう...
On top of dating, he likes your boobs too.
あ、もう、だって、もう魅力×2やん、みたいな。じゃあ、ずっと、このまま好きでい、いてくれ...
That's like Charm x 2! So he'll just keep loving you.
...続けてくれるな、みたいな、安心感。
That gives a sense of security.
いや、なんかさ...
No, actually...
思うのが...
I feel like...
なんかその、自分自身にとっての、おっぺーは、そんなに価値はあんま感じてなくて...
...I don't place much value on my own boobs.
ええーっ！？
Ehh?!
自分の？
Your own?
もったいない！
What a waste!
もったいないよ！
でも世の中には、そういうね、好きな人がいるっていうのは分かってるのよ、やっぱりね。
But I know there are people in the world who like them.
世間一般的に。
Generally speaking.
だから、ありがたいな、みたいには思うけど...
So I feel grateful for that, but...
それで、なんか、そういう、繋ぎ止められるとか強み、みたいな、自信には、至らないのかな...
...it doesn't give me confidence or make me feel I can tie someone down with it.
あー、なるほどね。
I see.
なるほどねー。
そう。ちょっと、余裕がない女なのかもしれない。
Maybe I'm just a woman who lacks composure.
ラミちゃんが...
Lamy-tan...
そう、自分の価値を見出したい、みたいな。たぶん自分自身がないからなのかな...
Wanting to find my own worth... Maybe I just lack self-confidence.
あー。
I see.
でもそういうところも、でもなんか可愛いけどね。
Even so, that part of you is so cute.
可愛いよ。
It's cute.
失言って言われてるので...
Calling "tying someone down" a slip of the tongue!
「繋ぎ止められる」は失言だったみたいですね。
"Tying someone down" was a slip of the tongue!
はい、では続いて、えっと...
Alright, moving on to the next one...
あ、これちょっと、え、答えてあげたいなという...
Here's one I'd like to answer.
「Snow Flowerのふたり、そしてゲストの団長こんばんは！」
"Good evening to the two of Snow Flower, and guest Noel Danchou!"
「私は現在、海外で生活しています。」
"I currently live overseas."
「現地の方から好意を寄せてくれておりますが...」
"A local resident has expressed affection for me..."
「私自身は数年後には日本へ帰らなければなりません。」
"...but I have to return to Japan in a few years."
「そのため、悲しい思いをさせるよりも、現地でもっとステキな方と過ごしてもらう方がいいのではと思ってしまいます。」
"Rather than making them sad, I feel it's better for them to spend time with someone wonderful locally."
「3人の意見をお聞きしたいです」という、ちょっと真面目モードですね。
"I'd like to hear the three of your opinions." A serious one.
あー、すごい、わー。
Ah, wow...
これ難しいね。難しいね。
This is tough.
気持ちは分かるね。
I understand how they feel.
そっかー。
I see.
でもなんか、正直に言ってあげてもいいのかなって思っている。
Honestly, shouldn't they just tell them directly?
あー、「数年後には帰らなきゃいけないよ」って。
Like, "I have to go back in a few years."
そう。だから、その... やっぱり難しいとは思うけど...
So, yeah... It's tough, but...
え、もう、なんか、そ、で、でも、愛してくれるなら...
Even so, if they love you...
日本に来るか、みたいな。
...they might even move to Japan with you!
うーん、難しいよね...
That's tough...
遠距離になっちゃうしね... 難しいね...
It would end up being a long-distance relationship. Tough.
「ついて来いよ」って。言え、っていうコメントもありますけど。
Comments say, "Tell them to follow you!"
どうでしょうか。
How about that?
あ、そう、積極的な... うん、そうだね。
For someone who is proactive...
寄せにきてくれてる人...
...and expressing their feelings...
ほんとにね、こよちゃんとかも言ってたけど、数年後には帰らなきゃいけないんだっていう話を言ったうえで...
...after discussing that you'll have to return in a few years...
悲しい思いさせるよりもとかはさ、相手側の、やっぱさ...
...saying "I shouldn't make them sad" is assuming for the other person.
気持ちだから、自分のそういう状況を伝えたうえでどうするかは...
It's their feelings, so explain your situation and let them decide.
...相手に委ねてもいいんじゃないかなって思ったり...
...is totally fine, isn't it?
...するかな。どうですか？
...is what I think. How about you?
うん、同意。なんかさ...
I agree.
やっぱ恋愛とかそういうのってさ、ファンタジーだと思ってて。
Romance and stuff is like a fantasy.
だから、なんか、こう理屈じゃないんじゃないかと。夢も持ってて...
It's not purely about logic. It's about holding onto dreams too.
だから、お互いのそういう、気持ちで...
So with mutual feelings...
なんか、こう、無理難解を乗り越えていくこともあるかもなんで...
...you might overcome difficult hurdles together.
ちょっと、気持ちを素直にいくのもいいんじゃない。なんか大人になりすぎなくても。
Being honest with your feelings without overthinking or acting too mature.
あ、確かにね。あー。
Ah, indeed!
すごい、いい言葉や。
That's a great line.
「大人になりすぎない」
"Don't act too mature."
って感じでした、団長は。
That's how Danchou feels about it.
なんで、ちょっと向き合ってみてください。
So try facing them directly!
はい、幸あれということで。じゃ、続いていきましょう！
Yes, may happiness be with you! Moving on...
え、こちらですね、えー...
Here's one...
女子ホロリスです。
From a college student...
「こんばんは！大学1年生の女子ホロリスです！」
"Good evening, I'm a college student!"
「こんにちは！大学1年の女子ホロリスです！」
"Hello! I'm a first-year college Holo-fan!"
「恋愛相談なんですけど...」
"I have a relationship question..."
「この前、他大学の男性と3回目のデートに行ってきました。」
"Recently, I went on a third date with a guy from another university."
「3回目なので、告白とか何かしらしてくれるかなと思ったんですけど、何もありませんでした。」
"Since it was the third date, I thought he might confess his feelings or something, but nothing happened."
「それから私の気持ちも冷めてきてしまって、LINEとかする気にも全くなれなくて...」
"After that, my feelings cooled down, and I lost all motivation to text him on LINE..."
「このままでいいのかなと悩んでいます。私はどうすればいいでしょうか？助けてー！」
"I'm wondering if this is okay. What should I do? Help me!"
「ふふ、可愛い。」
"Hehe, cute."
「お悩みでございます、ねえ。」
"Here's the dilemma, yeah."
「あー、3回目のデート。」
"Ah, a third date."
「3回目、どうなんですかね？」
"What do you think about the third date?"
「どうなんだろうな。」
"I wonder how it is."
「3回目のデート、何もありませんでした。」
"A third date, but nothing happened."
「え、これって、うん、」
"Wait, is this..."
「デートということは、え、これ付き合ってるってこと…？」
"If it was a date, wait, does that mean they're dating...?"
「付き合っては…ない！」
"They're... not!"
「ないけど、3回デートして…」
"They're not, but they went on three dates..."
「うん、3回一緒に出かけたなら…」
"Yeah, if they went out together three times..."
「もう、なんか告白とかそういう感じになるのかな、みたいな。」
"It feels like it should lead to a confession or something."
「思ってた…うん。」
"That's what she expected... yeah."
「なるほど。なんか冷めちゃったなら、もうそれが答えって…」
"I see. If her feelings cooled off, then that might be the answer..."
「うーん…て思う。」
"Hmm... I think so."
「男の子が奥手すぎて、本当は女の子のこと好きなんだけど…」
"Maybe the guy is just really shy, and even though he likes her..."
「うん、なんか告白する勇気がなくて…っていう」
"Yeah, he just doesn't have the courage to confess..."
「パターンもあると…なんだったら、そっちのパターンかなと思ってたけど…」
"There's that pattern too. I thought it might be that case, but..."
「コメントとか、結構「キープ」とかも言われてたりして…」
"Some comments are saying maybe he's just keeping her as an option..."
「あー、それはちょっと、あれだね。」
"Ah, that would be a bit..."
「むずいね。むずい。けど…」
"It's tough. Tough. But..."
「冷めちゃったなら…どうなんだろうな。なんか…」
"If her feelings cooled off... I wonder. Well..."
「3回目なので告白とかしてくれるかなっていう…」
"Hoping he would confess just because it was the third date..."
「ちょっと厳しいこと言うんですけど、っていう期待を…」
"To sound a bit harsh, having that kind of expectation..."
「してるのが、ちょっと、今後のためにもそう…」
"might not be the best mindset for the future either..."
「そういう価値観じゃない方がいいかもな、って思った感じがある。」
"I felt like having a different perspective might be better."
「というと？」
"What do you mean?"
「なんか、その3回目のデートでは告白するっていう決まりは全くなかったりとか…」
"Like, there's no rule that someone has to confess on the third date..."
「結構この世の中、告白せずになーなーで付き合った形になったみたいな人たちもいたりはするから…」
"In this world, there are people who start dating naturally without an explicit confession..."
「その…なんだろう…」
"So... how should I put it..."
「絶対起こるイベントではないので、なんか期待してなかったら冷めなかったのかなとか…」
"It's not an event that's guaranteed to happen, so if she didn't expect it, maybe her feelings wouldn't have cooled down..."
「そういう考えで見てもいいのかな、と思った。」
"I thought it might be good to look at it from that perspective."
「確かに。なんか、あれだね、多分…」
"Indeed. Well, it's like..."
「相手が何かやってくれる、男の子が…」
"Expecting the other person, the guy, to do something..."
「プロポーズしてくれたりとか、付き合ってって言ったりとか…」
"Like confessing, or asking her out..."
「受け身になってはいるよね、この子。」
"She is being pretty passive here."
「まあ、そうだね。」
"Well, that's true."
「女の子はね、願望としては確かに言われたいのはあるよね。」
"As a girl, the desire to be confessed to is definitely there."
「分かるよ。」
"I get it."
「分かる。だけど、でもね…」
"I get it. But, you know..."
「やっぱり人によっては…なかなか積極的な男の子じゃない子もいると思うし…」
"Depending on the person, some guys just aren't very assertive..."
「確かにそうだね。」
"That's true."
「付き合うってなると、そこら辺…」
"When it comes to dating, around there..."
「そうだね。好きだったら自分から動くのも…」
"Yeah. If she likes him, taking initiative herself..."
「大事だと思うから。」
"is also important, I think."
「「どうすればいいでしょうか？助けて」ということなので…」
"So since she asked 'What should I do? Help me'..."
「本当に、もうこれっきりこの男の子とはいいかなってなったら、連絡取らなくてもいいし。」
"If she feels completely done with this guy, she doesn't need to contact him anymore."
「まだ、本当ちょっと好きな気持ちがあるんだったら…」
"But if she still has even a little bit of feelings for him..."
「やっぱり行ってみるのいいと思うんだよね。」
"I think it's good to give it a try."
「ここで冷めちゃうの、ちょっともったいないな、って思うの。」
"Cooling off right here feels like a bit of a waste."
「だって3回目までデートに行ったんだもんね、事実。」
"Because they actually went on dates up to three times."
「時間割いてね。」
"Making time for each other."
「お互い時間使って会ってたわけなんだから…」
"They were using their time to see each other..."
「多分、向こうにも好意があることはあるんだろうね、だって3回目もデート行ったんだもんね。」
"So he probably has feelings for her too, since he went on a third date with her."
「でもやっぱり、ちょっと期待しちゃったんだね。」
"But yeah, she had high expectations."
「本当気になってるなら、自分からどんどん行っちゃってもいいんじゃないかな。」
"If she really cares about him, taking the initiative herself would be totally fine."
「そうだね。一旦、期待してた自分をなくして…」
"That's right. First, drop the expectations she had..."
「で、告白してくれなかったっていうのも全部なくして…」
"and forget the fact that he didn't confess..."
「その子が好きなのかどうか、っていうことを考えてみて…」
"Think about whether she actually likes him or not..."
「で、好きなら4回目行ってみようぜ！って。」
"And if she likes him, let's go for a 4th date!"
「誘ってみてもいいんじゃない？」
"Why not invite him out?"
「でも本当に気持ちが冷めちゃったんなら、無理していくことはないし。」
"But if her feelings really have cooled down, there's no need to force it."
「そんな気がします。」
"That's how I feel about it."
〜になってっていう感じだけど
It's kind of like that, but...
人に期待していいことは1つもないので、これは恋愛...
Nothing good comes from expecting things from people, so whether in romance...
恋愛でも恋愛じゃなくても
...or outside of romance...
そうね
That's true.
なんかやっぱり期待ってエゴなんで
I guess expectations are just ego, after all.
って思うと、ちょっと楽になるのかな、生き方が。
Thinking like that might make life a little easier to live.
思えるようになるとね。
Once you come to think that way, right?
はい。それでは続いて、えっと...
Right. Moving on to the next...
男の子ですね。
A boy, right.
えっと、グイグイ話しかけに来るのはどんな意図や背景を持っているのか、というお悩み相談でございます。
"What intentions or background does someone have when they approach so assertively?" is the advice topic.
えっと、同じ案件作業をしているが、直接会話が少ない後輩女性。
"A younger female colleague who works on the same project, but direct conversation is scarce."
職場飲み会開催場所移動前に、後輩女性から「今日の飲み会素敵ですよね。よく食べるとお聞きしたので、飲ませても大丈夫ですよね」みたいな社交的な会話が来る。
"Before moving to the venue for the work drinking party, she engages in social chat like, 'Today's venue is nice, isn't it? I heard you eat a lot, so it's okay to make you drink, right?'"
偶然にも座席の隣席が同じ場所。
"Coincidentally, we ended up sitting next to each other."
自分のコミュニケーションは高めと自負しているが、突然迫られると押し込まれるタイプ。
"I pride myself on having good communication skills, but I'm the type to feel pressured when suddenly approached."
何かあるのではと背景を見つつ、さりげない会話で終了。
"Wondering if there was something more, I observed her background while finishing with casual chat."
その後特に進展なし。今のご時世何があるかわからないという建前を置くチキン野郎です。年齢は30代前半です、と。
"No progress after that. A coward who uses 'you never know these days' as an excuse. Age in early 30s."
あー...
Ah...
こういう行動をとる女の子、もし自分がこの後輩女子だとしたら...
If I were this younger female colleague taking this kind of action...
どうなのかな、みたいな妄想ですね。
...what would I be thinking? It's that kind of hypothetical speculation.
これ、これはなんか...
Is this like...
相手が好意を持っているとかそういうのじゃなくて、なんでこう...
Rather than her having feelings for him, why would she...
どんな意図や背景を持っているんでしょうか、と。
"What intentions or background does she have?"
要するに、おそらく、この行動をしてくるって自分のこと好きなの？っていうのを...
In short, he probably wants to ask, "Does acting like this mean she likes me?"
女子ってどうなの？って聞き分けたいんだと思う。
...and wants to know, "How do girls see this?"
でも、あれだよね。実際に...
But, you know, in reality...
向こうからのアクションとしては、「今日飲み会来ますよね、いっぱい飲めますよね」って言われたこと...
As for her actual action, it was just saying, "You're coming to the party today, you can drink a lot, right?"
だけだよね？
...and that was it, right?
確かに今書いてある内容だとそれだけかも。
Indeed, based on what's written here, that might be all it is.
そう、同じ隣席とかはあったけど...
Yeah, sitting next to each other happened, but...
そんなに何にもなくても聞きかな、みたいな内容って感じ？
Is it the kind of comment someone would make even if there's nothing behind it?
まぁ...
Well...
なんか、飲み会に行くっていうきっかけがあるから、とりあえず...
Since there's an occasion like going to a drinking party, for now...
飲み会前でちょっとテンション、飲み会ってテンション上がるものかわかんないけど...
maybe her mood was up before the party—though I don't know if drinking parties raise your mood...
飲み会でテンション上がって、で、なんか話しかけたぐらいな感じなのかな？
...but maybe she got excited about the party and just decided to strike up a conversation?
ていう感じだよね、なんか本当に。
That's what it feels like, honestly.
まぁそうだね。でも内容としては「グイグイ話しかけに来る」っていうことも別であったのか、どうなのか...
Well yeah. But as for the description, was "approaching assertively" something separate that also happened, or what?
確かに回数の問題はあるかもね。
True, frequency might be a factor.
コメント欄は「何にもないぞ、安心しとけ」で一致しているみたいなんですけど...
It seems the comment section agrees on "There's nothing to it, stay calm," though...
でもなんか、もしすごい、そんなに俺にだけ話しかけてくる、みたいな...
But if it's like she's overwhelmingly approaching *only* him...
みんなに同じように... 飲み会の人数を増やしたくてみんなに言ってる可能性もあるかな...
...rather than everyone... There's a chance she's telling everyone to get more people to join the party too...
でも自分にばかりいろんなこと聞いてくるなってもし思うのであれば...
But if you feel like she's specifically asking you all sorts of things...
なんか聞いてみてもいいかなって思っちゃった。
...I almost think it'd be fine to just ask her.
「そんなに俺のこと気にしてくれてんの？」みたいな。
Like, "Are you that interested in me?"
ちょっと軽く。そんなにグイグイ来てるならこっちも軽く...
Just lightly. If she's coming on that strong, you can match it lightly...
ジャブ打つ？ ジャブ打つ。
Throw a jab? Throw a jab.
いやー、昨今... 昨今これ...
Man, these days... these days...
むずいんだよね、その...
It's really tough, that...
この方も心配してるしね、ちょっと。
This person is also worried about it, a bit.
だからもう、本当に何だろう...
So really, what should...
これでグイグイ系だったら... なんか、やっぱ昨今で結構...
If she's an aggressive type... well, these days it's pretty...
こよりダメそうだな、コンプラ違反で。
Koyori would get in trouble here for compliance violations!
こよちゃん、男の子でこういう悩める小羊だったら、ちょっとヤバかったかも。
Koyo-chan, if you were a guy and this was a lost sheep situation, it might've been bad!
女でよかったな、ギリギリ。
Good thing you're a girl, just barely!
グイグイ、まだ情報も薄いしってことは...
Since information is still sparse on her aggressive approach...
そんなに他でグイグイエピソードが揃ってないってことだから...
...that means there aren't many other instances of her being aggressive, so...
一旦、普通に仕事続けて自然な会話やってでいい気がするな。
...for now, just continuing to work normally and having natural conversations seems fine.
そうですね。そうだね。
Indeed. That's true.
して、多分、結構色んな人に話しかけるタイプの女性だったんじゃなかろうかという...
She was probably the type of woman who talked to a lot of different people...
性格な感じかもだな。
That might just be her personality.
「ふたりでご飯行きましょう」とか言われたら、もう一回考えてみたな。
If she said something like "Let me take you out to dinner, just the two of us," I'd reconsider.
あ、そうだね。感じかもね。
Ah, that's true. That might be the case.
はい。ということです。
Yes. So that's that.
はい！じゃあ、ちょっとあと2つ読んでもいいですか？
Alright! Can I read two more?
もちろんです！どうぞ、どうぞ。
Of course! Go ahead, go ahead.
女の子と男の子、それぞれ行こうと思うんですけれど、
I'm thinking of doing one for a girl and one for a boy...
可愛い奴です！「学生の女子隊員です！」
This one is super cute! "I'm a female student member!"
「高3。今絶賛片思い中なのですが、
"3rd year of high school. I currently have an unrequited crush, but..."
どうすれば相手に振り向いてもらえますか？モテる行動とか、
"...how can I get them to notice me? Please tell me..."
ヘアスタイルを教えてほしいです！ちなみにユニバのアトラクション、
"...some popular moves or hairstyles! By the way, we've ridden USJ attractions..."
ふたりで乗ったことあります。幸せ！」
"...just the two of us before. I'm so happy!"
可愛い！可愛い！
Cute! So cute!
はい、優勝！優勝！
Yes, automatic win! Automatic win!
可愛い！すごく可愛いんです！
Cute! She's so cute!
可愛いね！どうですか？
So cute! What do you think?
モテる行動とか、ヘアスタイル教えてほしいって！
She wants to know popular actions and hairstyles!
え、でもさ、その好きな男の子がさ、どんなスタイルが好きなのかにもよるんじゃない？
Well, doesn't it depend on what kind of style the guy she likes actually prefers?
そうなんだよね！
That's so true!
そう、この子に似合うとかも大事だったりするしな。
Yeah, whether it suits her is also important.
まあ、でも本当にひとつ言えるのは、もうすでに可愛い。もう、恋してる乙女、可愛いよ。
Well, one thing I can definitely say is she's already cute. A maiden in love is just adorable.
可愛い！可愛い！
So cute! Cute!
もう、いっぱい、いっぱい笑ってね。笑う女の子が一番最高やから。
Just smile a lot. A smiling girl is the absolute best.
確かに！愛嬌だよ、愛嬌！
That's true! Charm is key, charm!
男は度胸、女は愛嬌！
Courage for men, charm for women!
昔から言うよね！
That's what they always say!
いや、でも大事だと思うよ。笑顔。俺の前だとすごい一番この子笑ってくれるな、とかさ。
No, but it really is important. Smiling. Like "She smiles so much when she's with me."
絶対キュンとくるポイントでしょ。
That's definitely something that makes a heart flutter.
そうだね、本当。
That's right, truly.
なんかこの「可愛いな」って思ってるやつを、伝わるくらいニコニコししまくり、話しかけたりとかしてもいいのかなって。
I think it's good to smile a lot and talk to him enough that your feelings show.
そうだね。思っちゃいます。
Yeah. I agree.
大事、大事。そうだな。
Important, important. That's true.
自信持って、すでに可愛いので！あとはあれかな、
Be confident, you're already cute! Also, maybe...
もしヘアスタイルとか変えたいなら、「好きな女の子の髪型とかあるの？」って聞いて...
...if you want to change your hairstyle, ask him "Do you have a favorite hairstyle on girls?"...
次の日それをやってくる涼宮ハルヒですよ！
...and show up the next day wearing it, like Haruhi Suzumiya!
めちゃめちゃ意識してるじゃん！俺のこと！
"She's totally conscious of me!"
そういうのどう思う？可愛くない？
What do you think of that? Isn't it cute?
可愛いよね！
It's super cute!
そういうのやってみちゃってもいいかもしれないなって思います。
I think trying something like that could be really nice.
それやってなんか変な感じになったらどうしようってソワソワしてるんですけど...
I'm a bit nervous wondering what if it turns out awkward...
責任負えないな！
We can't take responsibility!
まあまあ、相手の男の内がどういう感じかわかんないからね。
Well, well, we don't know what kind of guy he is after all.
ねえ、でも可愛いでしょう。応援してます！
Right, but it's so cute. We're rooting for you!
それじゃあ、ラストは男子からのいこうかなと思いますけれど...
Alright then, for the last one, let me pick one from a guy...
どれにしようかな。
Which one should I pick?
もうホコホコしてる。本当に人の恋愛を感じるだけで...
My heart is so warm. Just hearing about other people's romance...
こちらですね、やっぱりノエル先輩ということで、ノエたん picnicということでね、はい。
Here's one, since Noel-senpai—Noe-tan is here, yes.
「大人の女性ならではの魅力をお持ちの、スバルとノエたんさんに質問です！」
"I have a question for Subaru and Noe-tan, who possess the charm unique to adult women!"
「私はいつか、素敵なお姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いをして、お互いに支え合えるような関係を築きたいと思っています。」
"Someday, I want to date a wonderful older-sister-type woman and build a relationship where we support each other."
「そこで質問なのですが、お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣や、こういう男性だといいなと思うポイントなどはありますでしょうか？」
"So my question is, are there any secrets to dating an older-sister type, or qualities you think make a great guy for them?"
「ぜひおふたりの意見やアドバイスを聞かせていただけると嬉しいです。」とのことです！
"I would be very happy to hear your opinions and advice!"
あらあら！大人の女性、あらあら！
My my! Adult women, my my!
大人のお姉さんに憧れている！
He longs for a mature older sister!
お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣！
The secret to dating an older-sister type!
お姉さんもね、色んなタイプがいるからね。ノエたんタイプのお姉さん...
There are all kinds of older sisters, you know. A Noe-tan type older sister...
ありがとう...
Thank you...
え、でも...そうだな...
Well, but... yeah...
なんか普通に...
Like, just normally...
変にさ、背伸びしなくて良くて...
you don't have to stretch yourself too far...
うんうん、一貫してるね。
うん、と思って...
Yeah, you're consistent.
Yeah, so I thought...
そう、なんか本当に...
Yeah, like, really...
こう真面目に...そう、生きて...
living so seriously...
なんか精一杯、精一杯で頑張ってる...
and trying as hard as you can...
ところとかを...
those parts of you...
なんか結構...あれなんじゃないかな...
might actually be what matters...
感じでちょっと難しい...自分がさ、お姉さん...
It's a bit tough, wondering if I'm even...
お姉さんタイプでいいのかと思いながら...
お姉さんだよ！お姉さん！
the "older sister" type myself, but...
You are! An older sister!
お姉さん！甘やかしてくれそう...
An older sister who seems like she'd pamper you!
っていうのが...なんかお姉さん感...
そうだね。
That vibe feels very older sister-like.
That's true.
なんか本当に、え、マジ...なんだろう...
Like, really, what is it...
精一杯、精一杯頑張ってる姿とか...
Seeing someone work as hard as they can...
が...ま、それはさ、なんかお姉さんとか...
regardless of whether they're an "older sister"...
関係なく、人として...なんか素晴らしいと思うからさ...
just as a person, I think that's wonderful.
だから、そ...そんな感じなのかな...
So, yeah, maybe it's something like that...
こういうところが良いみたいなさ、ピンポイントで言えなくて申し訳ないけど...
I'm sorry I can't pinpoint exact details like "this specific part is great."
一生懸命...
一生懸命ね。
Someone living...
Living earnestly.
うん、一生懸命なんか生きてる人は...
someone living their life earnestly...
すごい魅力的だなーって思う...
feels really attractive to me.
で、そういう人は甘やかしたいな...って...
And I feel like pampering someone like that...
今日仕事頑張った！
頑張った！頑張った！
"I worked so hard at work today!"
"You worked hard!"
褒めて！褒めて！
褒めて、褒めてー！
"Praise me! Praise me!"
"Praise me, praise me!"
ということですかね？
ってやっていいってことですよね？
So that's what you mean?
So it's okay to do that, right?
え、でもちょっと...思うんですけど...
Well, but I kind of think...
その、お姉さんに好かれるってなんかそのバブみとかさ...
being liked by an older sister, isn't that like...
あの...甘えるタイプがやっぱりお姉さんに好かれるのかなーみたいな...
being the pampered type that gets liked by older sisters...
2次元のというか、イメージ...
like a 2D trope image...
あー...
があるじゃないですか。
Ah...
that people have?
だからといって、その...
That doesn't mean you have to...
「バブ！バブー！」って生きる...ではないよなって思うんですけど、どうでしょうか？
live life acting like a total baby, right? What do you think?
いや...「バブバブー」は...ダメですか？
Well... is acting like a baby bad?
バブバブはダメですか？
Is "goo-goo ga-ga" no good?
いや、なんかそれもそれで可愛くてアリ...
あ、そう？
No, that has its own charm and works...
Oh, really?
ちょっと包容力が...ある...
You have so much motherly embrace...
アリ、アリだな...
It works, it really works!
だから本当に難しい...
So it's really difficult...
なんか...こういうことを言って、これ戦略だと...
If you treat this as a strategy...
思ってて...この...その、マロ主さんがどういうタイプ...
I wonder what type the questioner is...
こういうのってさ、あの...良し悪しとかじゃなくて...タイプの話じゃん、その自分は...
It's not about good or bad, it's about your type.
例えば背が高いから、そういう...なんかカッコイイ系で、なんかスタイリングとかしてますとか...
For example, if you're tall, you might lean into a cool style...
逆に「いや、自分結構幼い、童顔って言われるから...」
Or if you look young and baby-faced...
幼い感じで...とか...
you lean into a youthful look...
なんかそういう...なんの戦略？
That kind of strategy...
自分に合った感じとかも...
A style that suits you is important...
大事かなー...あと性格とかも...
And your personality, too.
だから...なんだろうな...
So... I wonder...
なんかどのタイプでも普通にお姉さんに好かれそうな気がする...
I feel like any type can be liked by older sisters normally.
精一杯に背伸びしてるタイプも、バブバブなタイプも...
Whether you're trying hard to act mature, or being babyish...
逆に...本当にNGなようなことをしなければ...
As long as you don't do anything obviously bad...
なんか良いな...って...
it can be nice...
清潔感！清潔感がある...
清潔感ね！
Cleanliness! Having cleanliness!
Cleanliness, right!
もうこれはあれだね、お姉さんとかお姉さんじゃないとかもう別で...
This isn't even about older sisters or not anymore...
関係なく人に好かれるということみたいな...
it's just about being liked as a person in general...
感じですかね？
right?
難しい...本当なんかちょっと...いや、むずいね...
It's tough... It really is a bit tricky...
こちら難しいんだけど...
This question is hard...
ま、人にもよるから、みたいなところはあるよね。
Well, it depends on the person, too.
ラミたん、お姉さん...とし...としたら...
Lamy, as an older sister...
ラミお姉さん属性ある？
Do you have "older sister" traits, Lamy?
あんまないかも...
あるあるあるよ！
Maybe not much...
You do, you definitely do!
でもみんな「お姉さんっぽい」って言ってるから、この人は。
But everyone says you seem like an older sister, this person says.
おー、そうなんだ。ラミに「お姉さん属性」...
Oh, really? Lamy has older sister traits...
いや、でも...
Well, but...
やっぱお姉さんあんま関係ないかもな、人としてになっちゃうな。
そうだな...
Maybe older sister traits don't matter much, it comes down to being a good person.
That's true...
ラミは、なんか尊敬できる...
For me, people I can respect...
人が魅力的に...
そうだね。
look attractive to me...
Right.
見えるから...
so...
お仕事を頑張ってるとか...
working hard...
なんか好きなことをね、追っかけてるとか...
or pursuing what they love...
なんかそういうのところに魅力を感じる...
I find charm in those aspects.
なるほどねー。
I see.
だからやっぱあれかね、誠実に...生きる...お姉さんとか一回置いておいて...
So living sincerely... setting "older sister" aside for a moment...
こよは？こよはどうなの？
What about Koyori? How about you?
私も「お姉さんなのかな？」っていう感じでは...
I also wonder if I count as an "older sister"...
あるんだけど...
type, but...
でもなんかやっぱり「支え合えるような関係を築きたい」っていう風に言ってるから...
Since they said they want to build a relationship where they can support each other...
それを大事にしていくことなのかなーと...
I think treasuring that is what matters most.
思えますね。で...
I think so. And...
その、でもなんか「お姉さんタイプの女性にとって」...
as for "for an older sister type woman"...
決めつけなくていいのかなと思っていて
I don't think you need to decide everything in advance.
好きになった人がお姉さんだったならお姉さんだし
If the person you fell for is an older sister type, then that's great,
もしかしたら全然お姉さんじゃない人を好きになるかもしれないから、この人自身も
but you might also end up falling for someone who isn't like that at all.
そのときに「お姉さんじゃないな」ってならないで
So rather than thinking, "Oh, they're not that type,"
好きになったなら、その好きになった人と幸せになってほしいなって思いまして
if you've fallen for them, I just hope you can be happy together with that person.
うん、幸せ。
Yeah, true happiness.
幸あれ！幸あれ！
Best wishes to them!
幸あれですね。
Indeed, best of luck.
なんかちょっとね、1個今の話の中でですね
Well, touching on what we were just talking about,
悩んでた人がいるので、1個だけちょっと取り上げていきたいんですけども
someone in the chat had a dilemma, so I'd like to read their message.
「質問です。女性から見て、恋愛や結婚に前かがみにならず
"Question: From a woman's perspective, what do you think of a man
自分のやりたいことに挑戦や目標に向けての行動を最優先して取り組んでいる男性ってどう思いますか？」って
who puts top priority on pursuing his goals and challenges rather than romance or marriage?"
いうのがあったんですよ。
That was one of the questions.
ええ！これ、あれ？付き合ってる彼女がいてってこと？
Ehh! Wait, does that mean he already has a girlfriend?
多分そういうことではなく、自分自身が恋愛とか結婚とか多分何も興味なく
It's probably not that, but rather that he himself has no interest in romance or marriage,
仕事に一生懸命なんだと思う。
and is just focusing entirely on his work.
「今仕事に一生懸命な人って素敵」みたいな話があったやん？
Earlier we talked about how people who work hard are attractive, right?
「どう思いますか？」っていうのは
So when he asks "what do you think?",
恋愛対象になるかな？みたいな話でも
he's asking if someone like that could still be seen as a romantic interest.
ちょっと考えてみると
If you think about it...
いや、もう良さしかなくて、今ちょっとあれなんですけど
Honestly, I only see good things in that, although...
なんだろうな、団長的に、個人的にね、思うのが...
How should I put it... Speaking personally, what I feel is...
めちゃめちゃやっぱり尊敬できるからさ、すごいなーって思う反面
I really respect that and think it's amazing, but on the other hand...
ただ、隙がないなーとも思うの。
I also feel like there's no room or opening to approach them.
もしかしたら近寄り難いみたいな、そういうところはちょっとある...
Like they might seem a bit hard to approach.
多分恋愛とかってさ、お互いの歩み寄りだったり、歩幅とかが違いすぎると
In a relationship, if your goals, pace, or effort are too far apart,
破綻しちゃうと思うから
I feel like it might just fall apart.
多分このマロ主さんは「すごくいいな」って団長は思ってたのって
When I thought this listener's attitude was really great,
団長もね、今こうやってホロライブでさ、活動すごくがんばっててさ
it's because I'm also working hard in Hololive right now,
お仕事に... こよちゃんが「うわー」って言ってるけど、お仕事に一筋みたいなところがあるから
focusing single-mindedly on work—Koyori is making faces, but—
なんか「同志だ」みたいな気持ちで思ったんだけど
so I felt a sense of camaraderie with them.
ただ、恋愛とか結婚とかしたい子からすると
But for someone who actually wants romance or marriage,
ちょっとあれかも。隙がなくて近寄り難いっていうのはあるかもなーって思ったら
having no openings might make you seem hard to approach.
素晴らしい！
Wonderful analysis!
拍手出てきた！
She even started clapping!
こよの顔ずっとニコニコやってたよ！
Koyori was grinning the whole time!
ニコニコというか、これすごく素敵じゃん。さっき2人が話してた内容も含めて「素敵やん」ってなるなって思って
Not just grinning, but like, "This is so great!" Combined with what you two said earlier, it's really nice.
でも、こよりは1個この子に伝えたいなって思ったことがあって
But there was one thing Koyori wanted to tell this listener.
それはすごく素敵なことだし、人間として素敵なんだけど
Doing your best is wonderful and great as a person,
「その生活をずっと続けてると何も起きないぞ、気付けろ」って
but "If you keep living that way forever, nothing romantic will happen, beware!"
こよりからの... 言うだけは言ってあげたいなって思ったのね。
That's what Koyori wanted to warn them about.
それを言って締めようかなぐらいに思って今これを取り上げたんですけど
I brought up this message planning to wrap up with that advice,
その理由がノエルたんの口から全部出たから、すごい拍手でした。
but Noel-tan explained all the reasons perfectly, so I couldn't help but clap!
解決策が出たと思って
A perfect answer was given!
その生活をしつつもちょっと「隙」を... 結婚とか恋愛とかしたいなと思ったら「隙」が必要なんですかね、多分ね。
While living that lifestyle, if you want romance or marriage, you probably need to leave a "gap" or opening, right?
隙って何ですか？隙？
What is a "gap"? An opening?
でも隙ってやっぱり、なんかさ、忙しそうにしてる...
Well, an opening means... if someone always seems so busy,
「やっぱり忙しいんだな」みたいな、「じゃあ
people assume, "Oh, they're super busy. Then
遊ぶ時間もないんだろうな」とか思われちゃいそうだから
they probably don't have time to hang out."
普通に趣味も楽しんでますよ、みたいな
So showing that you also enjoy personal hobbies...
あー、いいね！仕事だけじゃなくて
Ah, that's great! Not just work!
趣味を楽しんでるってことは「時間もちょっと余裕があって...」みたいな
Enjoying hobbies shows that you actually have some spare time...
そういうところかな？
Maybe something like that?
大々的に「恋愛興味あります」とかアピールできればいいけど、それってやりすぎると逆にね...
It'd be great to openly say "I'm open to romance," but if you overdo it, that can backfire too...
本当にそういう隙？趣味とか余裕とかかなって。
So having that kind of opening—showing hobbies or composure.
そこに「隙」を感じるということですな。
That's where people sense an approachable opening.
こよりが今学んでる！
Koyori is learning so much right now!
なるほどね。こよりじゃないからね。
I see. Because I'm not Koyori.
こよりが言えない、答えられない質問だからさ、これさ。
Because this was a question that Koyori couldn't really answer.
だから、ありがたいなと思って答えてもらったんだけど。
So I thought it was really kind of you to answer it for her.
ラミちゃんが女の子として好きだと感じるのは他にあったりする？
Is there anything else about Lamy that makes you like her as a girl?
え、でも、やっぱ趣味は大きいんじゃない？
Well, but having shared hobbies is pretty big, isn't it?
でもこの方、自分のやりたいことに挑戦してるって書いてあるから。
But this person mentioned that they're challenging themselves with what they want to do.
お仕事だけではなくて、自分のやりたいこともできてるってことでしょ？
So it means they're doing what they want to do, not just focusing on work, right?
すごくいいと思うけどね。めちゃくちゃ素敵だと思いますよ。
I think that's really great. I think it's wonderful.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
この人多分まだ好きな人とかいるわけじゃないと思うんだけど、
I don't think this person has someone they like yet,
趣味を満喫してそういう雰囲気を出すのに、ストラップとかつけてみるとか、
but to express their hobbies and vibe, maybe attaching a strap or key charm...
例えば我々のようなちいかわ好きだったら、キーホルダーつけてたりすると、
For example, if they like Chiikawa like us and attach a keychain,
「あ、ちいかわ好きで推し活したりしてるのかな」みたいなところから、
"Oh, they like Chiikawa," and from there,
会話が生まれたりとかね。
it might spark a conversation.
そういうのどうですかね？何にもつけてないとかだったら。
How about something like that if they don't have anything attached?
仕事とか、普段のそういうTPOにもよるけど、
It depends on work and everyday situations, but...
でも団長、めちゃいいなーって思った。
I thought that was a great idea, Noel.
それも好きではあるかなって思って。良いと思う。
I think I would like that too. I think it's good.
さっきのマシュマロの人も、ちいかわ一人で男性が見たいと言ってたけど、
Earlier, a guy in Marshmallow said he wanted to watch Chiikawa alone,
普通にそれって可愛いポイントだと団長思うから、
and Noel thinks that's actually a cute trait,
マスコットとか職場に付けていくなら物によるかもだけど、いいなって思う。
so depending on the mascot for work, I think it's really nice.
思います。そうですね。
I agree. That's true.
話しかけるきっかけになりそうですね。
It seems like a great conversation starter.
隙を作りつつ、お仕事頑張る君は素敵だよ、ということでね。
While creating an opening, working hard makes you awesome.
えらい！で、締めたいと思います！
Great job! And with that, let's wrap it up!
ちょっとお悩み拾いたいのがあって時間過ぎちゃったけど、今日はどうでしたか？
Sorry we ran over time answering questions, but how was today?
いやー、もう出れてよかった！楽しかった！
Ah, I'm so glad I could join! It was so much fun!
ガチトークだから、なかなか聞けない話が聴けたりして、
Since this is serious talk, we got to talk about real topics,
ガチな話いろいろ聴けたりできて、マシュマロでもね、
and hear so many honest thoughts. Even in Marshmallows,
悩んでる子がこんなにたくさんいるんだと思って。
I realized there are so many people struggling with things.
1点だけ！脱毛のデメリット言うの忘れてた！
Just one thing! I forgot to mention the downside of hair removal!
これだけ伝えたい！全身脱毛の話なんだけど、
I just have to say this! About full-body hair removal,
毛がないからさ、泡立たなくなった！ボディソープが！
since there's no hair, body soap doesn't foam up anymore!
えー！そんなことある！？
What?! Is that really a thing?!
今まで全身脱毛したことあるんだけど、
I've done full-body hair removal before,
昔は学生の時とか毛があったから、泡立ってたのよ、体が。
but back as a student, having body hair helped lather the soap.
だからわざわざゴシゴシするボディソープ泡立てるタオルとかあるじゃん。
You know those shower towels meant for lathering up body soap?
ああいうの使わなくてよかったんだけど、
I didn't need to use those back then,
毛がなくなったらツルツルで、泡立たせなきゃいけなくなった！
but without hair, it's so smooth I have to manually foam it!
毛で泡立ててたの？！そんなわけないでしょ！
You were lathering with your hair?! No way!
もしかしたら… どんだけ生えてたの？！
Maybe... How much hair did you have?!
ボディソープの問題じゃないの？
Isn't that just an issue with the soap?
脱毛考えてる人で「自分も毛で泡立ててた」人は気をつけて。
If anyone considering hair removal lathers with hair, beware.
真剣な話かと思ったけど… そんなことあるんだ！
I thought this was serious... I can't believe that!
泡々になるモショモショってなってるやつ使ってるんだけど、こより。
Koyori uses one of those mesh poufs that foams up easily.
泡立てができる網網になってるフワフワフワって集まってるやつ。
The mesh ones that gather into a fluffy ball to make foam.
あれ使えば最初から泡立って、そのまま滑らせればOKだね。
If you use that, it foams right away and glides over easily.
あれは画期的よね。
That thing is revolutionary.
全身脱毛する人はそれを買って…
So anyone getting full-body hair removal should buy one...
あ、そう！泡立てネット！
Ah, right! The foaming net!
あ、泡立てネットね。
Ah, the foaming net, right?
泡立... ま、そうなのかな？
Foam... Well, I wonder if that's so?
ま、そういう人もいるってことですね。
Well, that means there are people like that.
ちょっと個人差あると思いますけれど。
I think there are individual differences though.
泡立てネットおすすめなんで、ぜひ男子諸君も
Foaming nets are recommended, so guys, by all means...
使っていただければ。使ってください。
please feel free to use one. Please do.
でも、どうなんだろうね？
But I wonder how it is?
もちろん、すね毛とかそういうのは生えてなかったけど...
Of course, leg hair and stuff like that didn't grow, but...
男の人って、すね毛とか腕毛とか濃い人いるじゃない？
Men, some of them have thick leg or arm hair, right?
逆に毛がある人が使うと、毛がすごい絡まっちゃうかもしれないから...
On the contrary, if someone with hair uses it, it might get super tangled...
あ、泡立てネットが？
Ah, the foaming net?
うん。
Yeah.
毛が絡まることあるの？
Can hair really get tangled?
え、泡立てネットに？
Wait, in the foaming net?
剛毛だと...
If it's thick and coarse...
そう、剛毛でいっぱい生えてると、想像したけど、こうやって...
Yeah, if it's thick and there's a lot, I just imagined it like this...
なんかめっちゃつきそうだから、あれじゃない... その人は...
it seems like it'd catch a lot, so... that person...
それからはね、泡で手で...
From then on, with foam using their hands...
「ねえよ」って言われてる。「嘘、ないか」
People in chat are saying "No way!" "Lies, really not?"
分かんない、想像で話してたら...
I don't know, I was speaking from imagination...
泡立てネットの小さな穴の一つ一つに毛が入っちゃう...
Hair getting into every single little hole of the foaming net...
からまるのかなって。
and getting tangled, maybe.
剛毛ぐらいの毛だったら
If someone has really coarse hair,
一回やめて... お試しで使ってみるといいかもしれないですね。
they might want to test it out first before committing.
そうですね。なるほどなるほど。
That's true. I see, I see.
お気遣いありがとうございます。
Thank you for your consideration.
楽しんでもらえて良かったです。ありがとうございます。
I'm glad you enjoyed it. Thank you very much.
ラミちゃん、今日、話題はどうでしたか？
Lamy-chan, how was today's topic?
今日は、二人の体を隅々まで洗えることが確定したので...
Today, since it's confirmed that I can wash both of your bodies from head to toe...
確定？！
Confirmed?!
確定したので、洗う順番とかね、
Since it's confirmed, like the order of washing,
何を使ったらいいのかというのを、聞いておこうと思います！
and what to use, I thought I'd ask about that!
ありがとうございます！待って、それどうしよう？あ、はい。
Thank you! Wait, what should we do about that? Ah, okay.
え？じゃあ、こよは？
Eh? Then, what about Koyori?
こよは、ちょっと今のラミちゃんので、
As for Koyo, with what Lamy-chan just said,
本当に現れることがあるのだろうかと、
wondering if she really will show up,
男子小学生の気分になっているんですけれど...
I'm feeling like an elementary school boy right now...
来るかもよ？
I might show up, you know?
本当かもって、ちょっと今緊張してしまっているんですけれど...
thinking "Could it be real?", I'm getting a bit nervous...
でもやっぱゲストがいると、またラミこよとは別の
But having a guest brings out different values
価値観だったりが出てきて... ノエたんが
than Lamy and Koyori... and Noel-tan
とにかく優しいし...
is just so kind, and...
優しい！包容力！
So kind! So accepting!
結局何でも受け止めてくれそうだな、っていうので
It feels like she'd accept anything in the end,
なんかより好きになってしまいました。
so I ended up liking her even more.
嬉しい！団長も本当にさ、
I'm so glad! I also really...
このガチトーク出たかったから、今回ゲストに
wanted to appear on Gachi Talk, so being a guest this time...
出れて嬉しい！だけど、確かにこよちゃんが
makes me so happy! But indeed, as Koyo-chan
冒頭で言ってた、結構人を選んでしまうのではないか、みたいな...
said at the beginning, it might be a show that chooses its audience...
言ってたけど、団長は本当に
she said that, but I really hope
今後もこのガチトークが続いていって、
this Gachi Talk keeps going in the future,
このラインがOKなホロメンとかも出てきて、
and Holo members who are okay with this line of talk come on,
価値観とか色々聞けたら嬉しいなと...
and we can hear various values and perspectives...
待っておりますので！
We'll be waiting!
優しいな〜！
So kind~!
ちなみに、いつでも暇なんで、もしよかったら...
By the way, I'm always free, so if you'd like...
いつでも借り出して、永遠にゲストとか...
feel free to call on me anytime, as a perpetual guest...
無限ゲストだ！
Infinite guest!
「すのすのノエル」になる可能性がありますね！
It might become "Suno Suno Noel"!
お願いいたします！
Please do!
嬉しい！またね、やっぱり女子一人増えると
I'm so happy! Having one more girl
いろんな価値観があるんだなと思って、今日もすごく楽しかったです。
reminds us of all the different values, so today was super fun.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
またぜひノエたんも遊びに来てください！
Please come visit us again, Noel-tan!
はーい！遊びに行きます！
Yes! I'll come visit!
感想は「すのすの女子トーク」でぜひハッシュタグで
Please tweet your thoughts with the hashtag
つぶやいてくれたら嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！
#すのすの女子トーク, we'd love it! Thank you!
お願いします！
Thank you!
ということで、夜遅くまでありがとうございました！
So, thank you so much for staying with us until late at night!
それでは、おつガチトークで行きますか？
Shall we close with "Otsu-Gachi-Talk"?
はい！
Yes!
締めまーす！せーの！
Closing now! Ready, set...
おつガチトーク〜！
Otsu-Gachi-Talk~!
おやすみなさーい！
Good night, everyone~!
見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for watching!
また会いに来てね！
Come see me again!